(this["webpackJsonpagile-pm-questions"]=this["webpackJsonpagile-pm-questions"]||[]).push([[0],{37:function(e,t,o){e.exports=o(49)},42:function(e,t,o){},49:function(e,t,o){"use strict";o.r(t);var r=o(0),i=o.n(r),n=o(7),s=o.n(n),c=(o(42),o(26)),a=o(27),l=o(18),h=o(32),u=o(31),d=o(4),p=o(83),m=o(90),x=o(87),f=o(88),g=o(89),w=o(28),v=[{question:" Stakeholders must be prepared to accept that, as they understand more about the solution being developed ?",answers:[{text:"Change is inevitable",correct:!0},{text:"Change will always be a problem",correct:!1},{text:"Change must be restricted",correct:!1},{text:"Change will cause delays to the timescale",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which AgilePM principle is specifically supported by the concept of 'Build a one-team culture'?",answers:[{text:"Collaborate",correct:!0},{text:"Deliver on time",correct:!1},{text:"Never compromise quality",correct:!1},{text:"Build incrementally from firm foundations",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Agile Project Manager... :",answers:[{text:"..is expected to leave the detailed planning of the actual delivery of the product(s) to the Team Leader and members",correct:!0},{text:"..plans the detail of the actual delivery of the product(s), but validates the outcome with a Facilitated Workshop, in line with the AgilePM concept of empowerment",correct:!1},{text:"..is empowered to replace the Timebox Plans with better ones that s/he has created",correct:!1},{text:".. has to delegate responsibility to the Solution Development Team, but still needs to be the final decision maker for all day-to-day decisions, to ensure the right solution is actually created.",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these statements is true?",answers:[{text:"AgilePM can be used to complement other project management disciplines such as PRINCE2 and PMI without duplication of effort",correct:!0},{text:"AgilePM removes the need for using any other project management discipline such a PRINCE2\u2122 or PMI",correct:!1},{text:"Project managers need to decide whether to use PRINCE2\u2122 (or PMI) or to go agile",correct:!1},{text:"Choosing an AgilePM approach means that management becomes unnecessary",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM recognises four parameters, these are",answers:[{text:"Time, cost, features and quality",correct:!0},{text:"Time, cost, mandatory features, optional features",correct:!1},{text:"Must Haves, Should Haves, Could Haves, Won't Haves",correct:!1},{text:"Requirements, Time, Cost, Contingency",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does AgilePM state about the stakeholders attitude?",answers:[{text:"Stakeholders must be prepared to accept that change is inevitable as they understand more about the solution being developed",correct:!0},{text:"Stakeholders must be prepared to avoid change where possible in order to deliver on time",correct:!1},{text:"Stakeholders must be prepared to approve all changes, regardless of size or impact",correct:!1},{text:"Stakeholders must delegate all decision making down to the empowered team members",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these is a specific risk to an AgilePM project?",answers:[{text:"Swapping resources in and out of the team",correct:!0},{text:"Not having all the detail agreed at the start",correct:!1},{text:"The Business change their minds",correct:!1},{text:"Unwillingness to commit to final sign-off",correct:!1}]},{question:"What are the basic building blocks of the AgilePM approach?",answers:[{text:"Philosophy, Principles, Process, People, Products, Practices",correct:!0},{text:"Attitude, behaviour, team, deliverables, lifecycle",correct:!1},{text:"Deliver on time, communicate",correct:!1},{text:"Everything is negotiable, change is a fact of life",correct:!1}]},{question:"Delivering products on time ..",answers:[{text:"..is a desirable outcome for a project",correct:!0},{text:".. is something the business ask for but is unlikely to be achieved",correct:!1},{text:"..is not possible because the business keep changing their minds",correct:!1},{text:"..is far less important than delivering the whole solution",correct:!1}]},{question:"Collaboration ...",answers:[{text:"encourages increased understanding and greater speed",correct:!0},{text:"results in a lack of discipline within the team",correct:!1},{text:".. encourages the business to take over the project",correct:!1},{text:"..allows the team to deliver twice as much in half the time",correct:!1}]},{question:"In AgilePM",answers:[{text:"a solution has to be 'good enough', no more, no less",correct:!0},{text:"..quality will be reduced in order to meet the deadlines",correct:!1},{text:"..quality is negotiable right until the first Deployment",correct:!1},{text:"The highest level of quality is our goal",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does an Outline Plan contain?",answers:[{text:"A detailed plan for the work of the Foundations phase",correct:!0},{text:"A definition of the products in each Timebox",correct:!1},{text:"A full schedule of timeboxes and their agreed content, plus any other activities for the delivery of project products",correct:!1},{text:"A high level overview of the project, assessing its feasibility",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these statements is true.",answers:[{text:"Where a project is time-driven, choosing a traditional waterfall approach is very risky, because delivering 100% is the driving force rather than time being the driving force",correct:!0},{text:"Choosing a traditional (waterfall) approach is very risky, because this approach does not work",correct:!1},{text:"Choosing a traditional (waterfall) approach is very risky, because this approach does not work",correct:!1},{text:"The Project manager should have the final decision on the approach to be taken, since the Project manager owns the Risk Log",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these statements is true for AgilePM projects?",answers:[{text:"The level of business commitment for this project should be quantified and discussed in the early stages.",correct:!0},{text:"The level of business commitment on the project is negotiable, and must be increased if the project hits problems",correct:!1},{text:"Business commitment is requested on an ad-hoc basis, whenever the Solution Developers need advice and guidance",correct:!1},{text:"AgilePM projects only work if the business commit someone full-time to the Solution Development Team",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does AgilePM provide to help assess potential risk areas to be addressed?",answers:[{text:"Project Approach Questionnaire",correct:!0},{text:"Agile / Traditional Decision Table",correct:!1},{text:"Risk Assessment Questionnaire",correct:!1},{text:"AgilePM Applicability Questionnaire",correct:!1}]},{question:"In an AgilePM project...",answers:[{text:"requirements at Development Timebox level are stated in terms of Objectives",correct:!0},{text:"...requirement detail should be signed off by the end of Foundations",correct:!1},{text:"...requirement detail should not be documented; this is how infinite flexibility is achieved",correct:!1},{text:"requirements evolve; as the project progresses they become more detailed",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these statements is true?",answers:[{text:"AgilePM integrates a project management lifecycle and a product development lifecycle into a single framework",correct:!0},{text:"To be successful, AgilePM needs a waterfall project management lifecycle used alongside it",correct:!1},{text:"AgilePM has one framework for project management and a second framework for product delivery",correct:!1},{text:"AgilePM ensures successful agile product delivery, but needs the formality of a project management method to ensure agile does not get out of control",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these contain only AgilePM roles?",answers:[{text:"Business Ambassador, Business Sponsor, Technical Co-ordinator",correct:!0},{text:"Senior Supplier, Executive Sponsor, Business Visionary",correct:!1},{text:"Business Advisor, Business User, Business Visionary",correct:!1},{text:"Product Owner, Scrum Master, Team Members",correct:!1}]},{question:"Provided the team can demonstrate control over what they are doing, it is important that ....",answers:[{text:"the practice of \u2018management by exception\u2019 is employed by the Project Manager",correct:!0},{text:"the practice of 'management by control' is employed by the Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"the practice of 'management by absence' is employed by the Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"the practice of 'management by apathy' is employed by the Project Manager",correct:!1}]},{question:"As part of AgilePM\u2019s drive for clear and continuous communication, modelling",answers:[{text:"can offer significant benefits in making ideas, situations and options visible",correct:!0},{text:"can offer a way of avoiding formal communication",correct:!1},{text:"emphasises the need for applying formal modelling techniques",correct:!1},{text:"replaces the need for face to face communication",correct:!1}]},{question:"In AgilePM the quality of a solution is judged\u2026",answers:[{text:".on whether it contains at least the Minimum Usable Subset and whether all delivered requirements meet the agreed standard",correct:!0},{text:"on whether 100% of the requirements have been delivered",correct:!1},{text:"on whether all the Musts, Shoulds and Coulds have been delivered",correct:!1},{text:"on whether the customer signs off every requirement that has been delivered",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM says that [?] is sacrosanct and therefore cannot be adjusted",answers:[{text:"Time",correct:!0},{text:"The signed off Requirements spec",correct:!1},{text:"Timebox content",correct:!1},{text:"The lifecycle",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does AgilePM state about creating very detailed plans for more than a few weeks into the future?",answers:[{text:"This is wasted time and effort and can create a false sense of security, since it does not reflect the true sense of uncertainty",correct:!0},{text:"This is acceptable because the next step can be predicted with 100% accuracy but beyond that, no estimates or plans can be produced",correct:!1},{text:"This is unnecessary and creating fewer plans is a way of a good way saving paper",correct:!1},{text:"the Project Manager wants to do this, that is acceptable but the PM should leave the Team to focus on development work, not planning activities",correct:!1}]},{question:"In AgilePM, team members...",answers:[{text:".. organise their own work",correct:!0},{text:"take directions",correct:!1},{text:"compete",correct:!1},{text:"can slow down once the Must Haves have been achieved",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these behaviours would introduce risk into an AgilePM project?",answers:[{text:"Having a fully detailed specification at the start",correct:!0},{text:"Having a dedicated Solution Development Team",correct:!1},{text:"Having a part-time Business Ambassador",correct:!1},{text:"Having to produce a Business Case",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which AgilePM product includes an Outline Business Case and an Outline Solution?",answers:[{text:"Feasibility Assessment",correct:!0},{text:"Terms of Reference",correct:!1},{text:"Business Foundations",correct:!1},{text:"Solution Foundations",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which AgilePM lifecycle phases are completed sequentially and set the ground rules for the",answers:[{text:"Feasibility and Foundation",correct:!0},{text:"Pre-Project and Foundations",correct:!1},{text:"Foundations and Exploration",correct:!1},{text:"Engineering and Exploration",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of the following statements is true?",answers:[{text:"Models can be temporary, transient, throwaway or may be a prototype which forms part of the eventual solution",correct:!0},{text:"Object Oriented modelling is a mandated part of AgilePM",correct:!1},{text:"AgilePM encourages formal modelling techniques, preferably in an electronic format, so they can be properly controlled",correct:!1},{text:"Models are always temporary, and are superceded once the real work starts",correct:!1}]},{question:"The AgilePM ethos of on-time, on-budget delivery means that ...",answers:[{text:"some of what was originally envisaged for delivery during an Increment may have to be left out",correct:!0},{text:"an overtime budget should be agreed in the early stages",correct:!1},{text:"AgilePM should only be used on projects where quality is negotiable",correct:!1},{text:"the Agile PM should identify what additional Solution Developers may be available later in the project, if problems occur",correct:!1}]},{question:"Managing an AgilePM project is about",answers:[{text:"enabling constant change whilst continuously correcting the course of the project in order to maintain its aim on target",correct:!0},{text:"continuously correcting the course of the team in order to maintain its aim on target",correct:!1},{text:"keeping the team focused on the Project Plan whilst continuously correcting the course of the project in order to maintain its aim on target",correct:!1},{text:"trying to prevent drift from the specification",correct:!1}]},{question:"How does AgilePM reduce the risk of the business not knowing exactly what they want?",answers:[{text:"By using the high-level baseline created during Foundations and allowing the detail to emerge through Iterative Development",correct:!0},{text:"By using a combination of Facilitated Workshops and Modelling during Foundations in order to visualise, agree and sign off the full Requirements Specification",correct:!1},{text:"By building contingency into the estimates",correct:!1},{text:"By enforcing Timeboxing",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these statements is true?",answers:[{text:"MoSCoW prioritisation is really only meaningful in a specified timeframe",correct:!0},{text:"MoSCoW prioritisation is a way of getting more done in a shorter timeframe",correct:!1},{text:"MoSCoW prioritisation defines the sequence of work, with Ms being done first and Ws last",correct:!1},{text:"MoSCoW prioritisation ensures the technical needs of the project are addressed early in the project",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM advocates",answers:[{text:"..incremental delivery, in order to deliver real business benefit early",correct:!0},{text:"..daily delivery, since this is the objective of going agile",correct:!1},{text:"..delivery into production every timebox",correct:!1},{text:"..a single delivery, to reduce the overheads of deployment on the project budget",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these statements is true....?",answers:[{text:"Feasibility and Foundations set the ground rules for the iterative and incremental development of the solution that is to follow",correct:!0},{text:"Feasibility and Foundations are optional phases, used when the Project has some spare time at the start",correct:!1},{text:"Feasibility and Foundations are needed so that the Project Manager can get plans approved",correct:!1},{text:"Feasibility and Foundations are necessary to get the Requirements Specification signed off",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does AgilePM state about products?",answers:[{text:"Not all products are required for every project and the formality associated with each product will vary from project to project and from organisation to organisation",correct:!0},{text:"All products are required for every project, in order to ensure the correct process is being followed",correct:!1},{text:"Not all products are required for every project, and the Solution Development Team members  should agree at the start which ones will be omitted",correct:!1},{text:"Although creating the products is useful, the primary focus is to have everything in place by the end of the project",correct:!1}]},{question:"What is the correct definition of a Should Have?",answers:[{text:"A requirement that is painful to leave out, but the solution would still be viable",correct:!0},{text:"A requirement that is wanted or desirable but less important",correct:!1},{text:"A requirement that Should be with the customer as early as possible",correct:!1},{text:"The lowest priority requirement - one that will be the first to be dropped if a problem occurs",correct:!1}]},{question:"The most common purpose for measuring within projects is ..",answers:[{text:"to understand enough about progress to allow the outcome to be controlled",correct:!0},{text:"....to enable management to set performance targets",correct:!1},{text:"....to reward success and punish failure",correct:!1},{text:"....to be able to provide statistics to justify slippage",correct:!1}]},{question:"An AgilePM Project Manager should set the objectives for the teams but leave them to get on with it unless",answers:[{text:"the controls exceed any tolerances that may have been set by the project\u2019s governing body",correct:!0},{text:"the PM believes they are making the wrong decision",correct:!1},{text:"the PM can see a better way of doing things",correct:!1},{text:"Any of the controls (Time, Cost, Features, Quality) need adjusting",correct:!1}]},{question:"What product does AgilePM use to hold the work to be developed by the Solution Development Team?",answers:[{text:"Prioritised Requirements List",correct:!0},{text:"Product Backlog",correct:!1},{text:"Requirements Specification",correct:!1},{text:"To-do list",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does AgilePM state about Iterative Development?",answers:[{text:"Iterative Development needs to be controlled",correct:!0},{text:"Iterative Development needs to be constant",correct:!1},{text:"Iterative Development needs to be fun",correct:!1},{text:"Iterative Development needs to be quick",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM..",answers:[{text:"..encourages informal face-to-face communication at all levels",correct:!0},{text:"..avoids formal documentation",correct:!1},{text:"..encourages as many coffee breaks as you want",correct:!1},{text:"..replaces formal documentation with digital photographs",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM's use of well defined timeboxes",answers:[{text:"assist the Project Manager and the Team to 'Demonstrate Control",correct:!0},{text:"ensures the Project Manager is kept away from the Development Team",correct:!1},{text:"..provides detailed information for the Project Manager to put into Microsoft Project",correct:!1},{text:".. keeps senior management happy and allows the team to get on with doing real work",correct:!1}]},{question:"If all requirements are defined as Must Haves...",answers:[{text:"the flexibility derived from the MoSCoW prioritisation would no longer work",correct:!0},{text:"the business get the full solution in a shorter timescale",correct:!1},{text:"then the priorities will need to be re-negotiated at a later date",correct:!1},{text:"AgilePM still works well, but the risks are slightly higher than usual",correct:!1}]},{question:"During the Investigation iteration of a Solution Development Timebox, why is it necessary to understand the full detail of all the work intended for completion in the Timebox?",answers:[{text:"To allow informed decisions later in the Timebox about what lower priority requirements maybe dropped if necessary",correct:!0},{text:"To allow the Agile PM to complete a properly detailed project plan",correct:!1},{text:"To allow the Business Ambassador to be confident the Team will be working hard",correct:!1},{text:"To highlight what work is highly unlikely to get done in the Timebox",correct:!1}]},{question:"In AgilePM, the quality of the solution is judged on",answers:[{text:"Whether it contains at least the Minimum Usable Subset",correct:!0},{text:"Whether it contains the Shoulds and Coulds",correct:!1},{text:"Whether it contains at least all the Musts and Shoulds",correct:!1},{text:"Whether all the requirements have been delivered",correct:!1}]},{question:"At which point in the Development Timebox are the Timebox objectives reviewed to gain a common understanding of what is to be achieved?",answers:[{text:"Timebox Kick-off",correct:!0},{text:"Investigation",correct:!1},{text:"Consolidation",correct:!1},{text:"Refinement",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which planning product do the Solution Development Team use to record what they will be working on in the next few weeks, together with their MoSCoW priorities?",answers:[{text:"The Timebox Plan",correct:!0},{text:"The Delivery Plan",correct:!1},{text:"The Deployment Plan",correct:!1},{text:"The Development Approach",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does AgilePM state as a benefit of Facilitated Workshops?",answers:[{text:"Building consensus",correct:!0},{text:"Building co-location",correct:!1},{text:"Building solutions",correct:!1},{text:"Building flow charts",correct:!1}]},{question:"'The skill and [?] of the Workshop Facilitator is important to ensure successful workshops'",answers:[{text:"independence",correct:!0},{text:"personality",correct:!1},{text:"versatility",correct:!1},{text:"power",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Daily Stand Up provides the primary mechanism for ...",answers:[{text:"the Team Leader to track progress and exert the necessary control over the work of the team to ensure on-time delivery",correct:!0},{text:"a team get-together during coffee break",correct:!1},{text:"...the Solution Developers to demonstrate the Evolving Solution",correct:!1},{text:"...the Solution Developers to apportion blame when things are not going well",correct:!1}]},{question:"In Timeboxing, significant change (for example, addition of additional requirements that cannot be traced back to the baseline created in Foundations ).",answers:[{text:"should be considered to be a change of scope and may require a more formal change control process",correct:!0},{text:"..should be encouraged as this is what teams expect",correct:!1},{text:"..should be tolerated and accommodated in existing plans and deadlines",correct:!1},{text:"should be refused under all circumstances",correct:!1}]},{question:"When creating a schedule of Timeboxes, the primary driver should always be",answers:[{text:"the business priority",correct:!0},{text:"the technical preferences",correct:!1},{text:"The Outline Plan",correct:!1},{text:"the view of the Project Manager",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these statements is true for AgilePM?",answers:[{text:"Increments are divided into Development Timeboxes",correct:!0},{text:"Development Timeboxes are subdivided into Increments",correct:!1},{text:"Increments are divided into Iterations",correct:!1},{text:"Each Development Timebox is immediately followed by an Increment",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these statements is true?",answers:[{text:"Scalability is a key attribute of AgilePM.",correct:!0},{text:"Scalability is a problem for AgilePM",correct:!1},{text:"AgilePM fits all shapes and sizes of project without any need for tailoring",correct:!1},{text:"AgilePM should not be used except on small projects",correct:!1}]},{question:"An AgilePM project should be able to demonstrate ...",answers:[{text:"predictability and control in a rapidly changing agile environment",correct:!0},{text:"predictability through controlling change",correct:!1},{text:"agility through removal of constraints",correct:!1},{text:"flexibility. Anything that delivers the end goal is acceptable",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM expects early estimates",answers:[{text:"to give a broad picture, sufficient only to support the decision on whether or not to proceed",correct:!0},{text:"to lay down a precise shape for the project",correct:!1},{text:"to contain actual results and measures of velocity",correct:!1},{text:"to use function point analysis",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these statements is true for AgilePM?",answers:[{text:"Re-estimation happens throughout the project. Use MoSCoW prioritisation to remain on track",correct:!0},{text:"Re-estimation happens until the end of Foundations, when the Delivery Plan is issued",correct:!1},{text:"Re-estimation should only be carried out during the early Development Timeboxes",correct:!1},{text:"Re-estimation happens throughout the project. Use Iterative Development to remain on track",correct:!1}]},{question:"It is important to capture information on how much time is spent on delivering the products in order to..",answers:[{text:"ease the task of further estimating",correct:!0},{text:"identify the more productive members of the team",correct:!1},{text:"identify team members who are not as good as they should be",correct:!1},{text:"publish results of different teams in a league table",correct:!1}]},{question:"Within the Deployment phase there are three sub-phases or sections, what are they?",answers:[{text:"Assemble, review, deploy",correct:!0},{text:"Feasibility review, iterative development, release planning",correct:!1},{text:"Daily stand-ups, collaboration, deployment",correct:!1},{text:"Evolutionary development, foundations, pre-project",correct:!1}]},{question:"What role is responsible for the business case and project budget?",answers:[{text:"Business Sponsor",correct:!0},{text:"Business Visionary",correct:!1},{text:"Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"Business Analysis",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of the following is a benefit of using DSDM?",answers:[{text:"The risk of building the wrong solution is substantially reduced",correct:!0},{text:"A decreased reliance on customer collaboration",correct:!1},{text:"Less iterations needed to complete your project",correct:!1},{text:"The staff required to build a solution is substantially reduced",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does the 'S' in MoSCoW stand for?",answers:[{text:"Should have",correct:!0},{text:"Should not have",correct:!1},{text:"Standardization",correct:!1},{text:"Support Team",correct:!1}]},{question:"What are the two styles of timeboxes that DSDM recognizes?",answers:[{text:"Structured and free format",correct:!0},{text:"Daily stand-up and structured",correct:!1},{text:"Investigation and Refinement",correct:!1},{text:"Kick-off and Daily stand-up",correct:!1}]},{question:"The foundations phase occurs after the feasibility phase.",answers:[{text:"Correct",correct:!0},{text:"Incorrect",correct:!1},{text:"Half correct",correct:!1},{text:"Quarter correct",correct:!1}]},{question:"What is the purpose of a DSDM Coach?",answers:[{text:"They are responsible for helping the team understand the DSDM approach and help those outside of the team understand the process.",correct:!0},{text:"They are responsible for motivating the team to complete each evolutionary iteration",correct:!1},{text:"They manage the workshop process and are responsible for organizing workshop meetings",correct:!1},{text:'They are tasked with providing "Agile-style leadership"',correct:!1}]},{question:"During the foundations phase, you go through your iterative development process.",answers:[{text:"Incorrect",correct:!0},{text:"Correct",correct:!1},{text:"Half correct",correct:!1},{text:"Quarter correct",correct:!1}]},{question:"If you are nearing a deadline, compromising quality is an acceptable trade-off in DSDM",answers:[{text:"Incorrect",correct:!0},{text:"Correct",correct:!1},{text:"Half correct",correct:!1},{text:"Quarter correct",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which roles are part of the Project Level in DSDM?",answers:[{text:"Business Sponsor, Business Visionary, Technical Coordinator",correct:!0},{text:"Business Analyst, Project Manager, Business Ambassador",correct:!1},{text:"Technical Coordinator, Technical Adviser, Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"Business Sponsor, DSDM Coach, Team Leader",correct:!1}]},{question:"What is Agile-Style leadership?",answers:[{text:"A servant-leader, not an authoritarian leader",correct:!0},{text:"An authoritarian leader, not a servant-leader",correct:!1},{text:"A team leader on the Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!1},{text:"Another name for a project manager of an Agile team",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does the 'W' stand for in MoSCoW?",answers:[{text:"Won't have this time",correct:!0},{text:"Would like to have this time",correct:!1},{text:"Want to have this time",correct:!1},{text:"Wish to have this time",correct:!1}]},{question:"A structured timebox contains three steps:",answers:[{text:"Investigation, refinement, consolidation\n",correct:!0},{text:"Investigation, review, collaboration",correct:!1},{text:"Free format, review, consolidation",correct:!1},{text:"Kick-off, refinement, collaboration",correct:!1}]},{question:"Who is responsible for leading a self-empowered team using facilitation rather than an authoritarian approach to leadership?",answers:[{text:"Project Manager",correct:!0},{text:"Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"Business Sponsor",correct:!1},{text:"DSDM Coach",correct:!1}]},{question:"Fill in the blank. The __________ represents the business needs to the solution development team.",answers:[{text:"Business Ambassador",correct:!0},{text:"Business Analyst",correct:!1},{text:"Business Visionary",correct:!1},{text:"Project Manager",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which is NOT one of the 8 Principles of DSDM?",answers:[{text:"Individuals and interactions over processes and tool",correct:!0},{text:"Focus on the business need",correct:!1},{text:"Never compromise quality",correct:!1},{text:"Communicate continuously and clearly",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does the acronym SDT stand for?",answers:[{text:"Solution Development Team",correct:!0},{text:"Software Development Team",correct:!1},{text:"Standard DSDM Testing",correct:!1},{text:"Structured Development Timebox",correct:!1}]},{question:"For DSDM, the timebox duration of the daily stand-up should be:",answers:[{text:"2 minutes per person + 2 minutes",correct:!0},{text:"15 minutes",correct:!1},{text:"3 minutes per person + 3 minutes",correct:!1},{text:"20 minutes",correct:!1}]},{question:"'Must Have' items provide the Minimum Usable SubseT (MUST) of requirements which a project guarantees to deliver.",answers:[{text:"Correct",correct:!0},{text:"Incorrect",correct:!1},{text:"Half correct",correct:!1},{text:"Quarter correct",correct:!1}]},{question:"Fill in the blank. The __________ is an evolutionary product that provides a high-level definition of tools, techniques, customs, practices, and standards that will apply to the evolutionary development of the solution.",answers:[{text:"Development Approach Definition",correct:!0},{text:"Solution Architecture Definition",correct:!1},{text:"Delivery Plan",correct:!1},{text:"Management Approach Definition",correct:!1}]},{question:"In a structured timebox, the investigation phase should consume more than 10-20% of effort",answers:[{text:"Correct",correct:!0},{text:"Incorrect",correct:!1},{text:"Half correct",correct:!1},{text:"Quarter correct",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role should ideally be filled by someone elected by their peers?",answers:[{text:"Team Leader",correct:!0},{text:"Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"Business Ambassador",correct:!1},{text:"DSDM Coach",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which phase of the DSDM lifecycle do you do just enough work to determine if further planning is acceptable to the organization's goals?",answers:[{text:"Feasibility",correct:!0},{text:"Pre-project",correct:!1},{text:"Foundations",correct:!1},{text:"Deployment",correct:!1}]},{question:"An effective and successful team requires four elements. What are they?",answers:[{text:"Empowerment, stability, skills, size",correct:!0},{text:"Investigation, refinement, consolidation, close-out",correct:!1},{text:"Active, stable, committed, resourceful\n",correct:!1},{text:"Iterative development, continuously improving, empowered, skills",correct:!1}]},{question:"Fill in the blank. 'Could Have' items should typically only make up about ______ of total effort in a given iteration.",answers:[{text:"20%",correct:!0},{text:"60%",correct:!1},{text:"10 hours",correct:!1},{text:"10%",correct:!1}]},{question:"What is the Solution Architecture Definition?",answers:[{text:"An evolutionary product that covers both business and technical aspects of the solution",correct:!0},{text:"An evolutionary product that is designed for the solution development team laying out the definition of tools, techniques, and standards they will utilize in development of the solution",correct:!1},{text:"A feasibility product that provides a snapshot of the evolving solution",correct:!1},{text:"An evolutionary product that lays how the solution development team will deliver the final solution",correct:!1}]},{question:"hat are the two distinct type of products defined in DSDM?",answers:[{text:"Evolutionary products and milestone products",correct:!0},{text:"Roles and responsibilities",correct:!1},{text:"Terms of reference and the solution design",correct:!1},{text:"Documentation and the solution",correct:!1}]},{question:"When should the first instance of a solution be fully tested and potentially ready for deployment?",answers:[{text:"At the review stage of deployment",correct:!0},{text:"At the assemble stage of deployment",correct:!1},{text:"During the development iteration during that instance of the solution",correct:!1},{text:"At the evolutionary development stage",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does NOT occur in the Foundations phase of the DSDM lifecycle?",answers:[{text:"The first or foundational instance of development",correct:!0},{text:"Developing a strategy for deployment",correct:!1},{text:"Being able to commit to the delivery date of the first increment",correct:!1},{text:"A rough schedule of how many iterations needed and the duration of the iterations",correct:!1}]},{question:"The business analyst is not part of the solution development team",answers:[{text:"Incorrect",correct:!0},{text:"Correct",correct:!1},{text:"Half correct",correct:!1},{text:"Quarter correct",correct:!1}]},{question:"In a structured timebox, which step encompasses the bulk of the development, requirements work and testing of the timebox products?",answers:[{text:"Refinement",correct:!0},{text:"Investigation",correct:!1},{text:"Consolidation",correct:!1},{text:"Review",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of the below is NOT a valid reason to assign a work item to a 'Must Have' status using MoSCoW prioritization?",answers:[{text:"It is important, but not critical",correct:!0},{text:"Not legal to leave it out",correct:!1},{text:"Product is unsafe without it",correct:!1},{text:"Solution will not function if it does not contain it",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Solution Developer is tasked with making sure the solution works",answers:[{text:"Incorrect",correct:!0},{text:"Correct",correct:!1},{text:"Half correct",correct:!1},{text:"Quarter correct",correct:!1}]},{question:"The business case is an evolutionary product that provides vision and justification for the project from the perspective of the business.",answers:[{text:"Correct",correct:!0},{text:"Incorrect",correct:!1},{text:"Half Incorrect",correct:!1},{text:"Quarter Incorrect",correct:!1}]},{question:"What is the Prioritized Requirements List (PRL)?",answers:[{text:"It is a high-level definition of the requirements that will be addressed by the project",correct:!0},{text:"It is an extremely detailed definition of the requirements that will be addressed by the project",correct:!1},{text:"It is a high-level design of the framework for the overall solution",correct:!1},{text:"It provides the definition of tools, techniques, customs, practices, and standards that will be applied to the development of the solution",correct:!1}]},{question:"What is the point of a timebox kick-off?",answers:[{text:"Review timebox objectives and gain a common understanding of the expected achievements",correct:!0},{text:"Provide a firm foundation for the work to be carried out by further clarifying requirements",correct:!1},{text:"Work to complete the planned development activities for the timebox",correct:!1},{text:"Gain formal acceptance of the products delivered from the timebox",correct:!1}]},{question:"What is the duration of a close-out for a structured timebox",answers:[{text:"Approximately 1-3 hours for a 2-3 week timebox",correct:!0},{text:"4 hours",correct:!1},{text:"8 hours for a month long sprint",correct:!1},{text:"Approximately 10-20% of the timebox",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Technical Coordinator is responsible for promoting appropriate standards of technical best practices.",answers:[{text:"Correct",correct:!0},{text:"Incorrect",correct:!1},{text:"Half incorrect",correct:!1},{text:"Quarter incorrect",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Business Analyst is responsible for encouraging full participation of team members within their defined roles.",answers:[{text:"Incorrect",correct:!0},{text:"Correct",correct:!1},{text:"Half correct",correct:!1},{text:"Quarter correct",correct:!1}]},{question:"Involving the right people at the right time falls under which of the 8 principles?",answers:[{text:"Collaborate",correct:!0},{text:"Build Incrementally from Firm Foundations",correct:!1},{text:"Communicate Continuously and Clearly",correct:!1},{text:"Focus on the Business Need",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does AgilePM state about the business case?",answers:[{text:"AgilePM teams will establish a sound business case",correct:!0},{text:"A business case is irrelevant for an Agile project",correct:!1},{text:"AgilePM teams will avoid creating a business case if possible",correct:!1},{text:"A business case to agree project funding needs to be approved before closing down the project",correct:!1}]},{question:"1. AgilePM is focused on ________.",answers:[{text:"value delivery",correct:!0},{text:"project realization",correct:!1},{text:"benefits delivery",correct:!1},{text:"style of working",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM promotes ________.",answers:[{text:"BDUF - Big Design Up Front",correct:!1},{text:"EDUF - Enough Design Up Front",correct:!0},{text:"NDOF - No Design Up Front",correct:!1},{text:"DDUF - Detailed Design Up Front",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which questions are appropriate to ask before starting an AgilePM project?",answers:[{text:"Simple or Complex Environment?",correct:!0},{text:"Delivering Projects or Changing Service?",correct:!1},{text:"Maximum formality within a structured corporate culture?",correct:!1},{text:"Formalized contact with client / business?",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM states that:",answers:[{text:"quality and value are same things",correct:!1},{text:"nothing is build ideal for a first time",correct:!0},{text:"people require monitoring and close supervisor",correct:!1},{text:"users cannot define requirements",correct:!1}]},{question:"Agile to be successful requires ________?",answers:[{text:"on time delivery, according to business priorities",correct:!0},{text:"communication via chat",correct:!1},{text:"acceptance that change must be controlled",correct:!1},{text:"understanding of business requirements and wants",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which are characteristics of Self Directed Teams (AgilePM)?",answers:[{text:"comply with processes, regardless of outcome",correct:!1},{text:"compete",correct:!1},{text:"continuously look for better ways of working",correct:!0},{text:"focus on low-level objectives",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which is an AgilePM principle?",answers:[{text:"Focus on Benefits",correct:!1},{text:"Test Continuously",correct:!1},{text:"Clarify and Refine",correct:!1},{text:"Never Compromise Quality",correct:!0}]},{question:"How is AgilePM managing Change Management?",answers:[{text:"Baseline prototype, at least at the end of Development Timebox",correct:!0},{text:"Manage change in every element in project",correct:!1},{text:"Change is not recommended",correct:!1},{text:"Few, or even no baselines",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does AgilePM state as 4 project parameters?",answers:[{text:"Time, cost, quality and benefits",correct:!1},{text:"Time, facilities, results, benefits",correct:!1},{text:"Cost, quality, time, features",correct:!0},{text:"Quantity, time, cost, future",correct:!1}]},{question:"Self Directed Teams (Agile) ________.",answers:[{text:"take directions",correct:!1},{text:"are always collocated",correct:!1},{text:"continuously look for better ways of working",correct:!0},{text:"rigorously comply with procedures",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of these is an AgilePM principle?",answers:[{text:"Communicate often",correct:!1},{text:"Communicate verbally",correct:!1},{text:"Communicate formally",correct:!1},{text:"Communicate continuously and clearly",correct:!0}]},{question:"One of characteristics of AgilePM ________.",answers:[{text:"similar style of management like traditional",correct:!1},{text:"strictly adhering to project plan",correct:!1},{text:"measured by delivery of products (not by activity)",correct:!0},{text:"measured by project plan progress",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM ________.",answers:[{text:"keeps business and product delivery on track",correct:!1},{text:"sets team objectives, then lets them get on with it",correct:!0},{text:"sustains corporate culture and organizational structure",correct:!1},{text:"manages support office involvement with team",correct:!1}]},{question:"In Agile, quality consists of ________.",answers:[{text:"product and acceptance criteria",correct:!1},{text:"fit for purpose documentation and good quality product",correct:!1},{text:"good business analysis and effective change management process",correct:!1},{text:"process and solution",correct:!0}]},{question:"During Foundation AgilePM recommends about final decision to one of three maintainability levels, which is    one of them?",answers:[{text:"deliver perfectly, with no errors",correct:!1},{text:"deliver first, re-engineer later",correct:!0},{text:"short-term, strategic solution",correct:!1},{text:"create prototype, test, deploy",correct:!1}]},{question:"What AgilePM says about quality and Gateway Reviews?",answers:[{text:"Gateway reviews are only for traditional sequential projects",correct:!1},{text:"Gateway reviews are only for programmes",correct:!1},{text:"Gateway reviews are used as a formalized tool to assess any project health",correct:!0},{text:"Gateway reviews should be done only at project start",correct:!1}]},{question:"When acceptance criteria for each product in Development Timebox need to be agreed?",answers:[{text:"During Feasibility study",correct:!1},{text:"During Foundations",correct:!1},{text:"During Kick-Off",correct:!0},{text:"During Development Timeboxes",correct:!1}]},{question:"In which scenarios quality was not managed correctly according to AgilePM?",answers:[{text:"The delivered solution fails to meet the business need",correct:!0},{text:"The delivered solution has only core functionality",correct:!1},{text:"The delivered solution has an several minor number of flaws",correct:!1},{text:"The delivered solution has minimal functionality",correct:!1}]},{question:"What is an Engineering phase?",answers:[{text:"The AgilePM phase used iteratively and incrementally to evolve the solution created during        Exploration.    ",correct:!0},{text:"The AgilePM phase which is used iteratively and incrementally to investigate the detailed requirements        and translate them into a form which can then be evolved into a viable solution.    ",correct:!1},{text:"The AgilePM phase which gives the first opportunity for deciding whether or not the project is viable        from a technical or business perspective.    ",correct:!1},{text:"The AgilePM phase to establish firm and enduring foundations from the three perspectives on a project of        business, solution and management.    ",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM is an agile project delivery framework that delivers:",answers:[{text:"A good solution to specification",correct:!1},{text:"The right solution at the right time",correct:!0},{text:"Suitable Solutions to cost and scope",correct:!1},{text:"Any solution to quality",correct:!1}]},{question:"The aim of all project management is to deliver the right output:",answers:[{text:"On time and on budget using the available resources wisely",correct:!0},{text:"To the defined level of functionality agreed at the outset",correct:!1},{text:"Within the constraints of risk imposed by the Business Sponsor",correct:!1},{text:"Whatever the cost, time or resources needed",correct:!1}]},{question:"Development Timebox planning represents which level of planning within an AgilePM project?",answers:[{text:"Highest",correct:!1},{text:"Best",correct:!1},{text:"Lowest",correct:!0},{text:"Earliest",correct:!1}]},{question:"In AgilePM projects how many levels of decision making are normally present?",answers:[{text:"Two: steering level and project level",correct:!1},{text:"Three: steering level, project level and team level",correct:!0},{text:"Four: steering level, project level, business level and team level",correct:!1},{text:"Three: project level, solution development level and other",correct:!1}]},{question:"In an Agile project it is vital that stakeholder buy into?",answers:[{text:"The Products",correct:!1},{text:"The processes",correct:!1},{text:"The Principles",correct:!1},{text:"The Philosophy",correct:!0}]},{question:"Early delivery of real benefits to the business is best achieved when key stakeholders understand the    business objectives and experience which of the following?",answers:[{text:"Empowerment and collaboration",correct:!0},{text:"Indifference and commitment",correct:!1},{text:"Collaboration and autonomy",correct:!1},{text:"Detailed planning and quality assurance",correct:!1}]},{question:"Why will everybody concerned with the development team know what is happening?",answers:[{text:"They are part of a small team working closely together",correct:!0},{text:"There are regular and full reports by the Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"Every day begins with a full review of the status of the whole project",correct:!1},{text:"People are given time to inquire of other teams as necessary",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM's Project Approach Questionnaire (PAQ) provides a good starting point for:",answers:[{text:"Creating a clear understanding of project risks and their mitigation",correct:!0},{text:"Ensuring that the project will be capable of being managed by the Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"Providing a risk free environment for the project",correct:!1},{text:"Delivering a product which conforms to the specification agreed at the outset",correct:!1}]},{question:"There is a perception that risk management is a Project Manager responsibility. However in reality:",answers:[{text:"The Business Sponsor should manage all risks",correct:!1},{text:"The whole team should be aware of the risks",correct:!0},{text:"The Project Manager should never undertake the management of risk",correct:!1},{text:"The development team manager should take care of all risks",correct:!1}]},{question:"On what should the project team and other significant stakeholders remain focused?",answers:[{text:"The business outcome",correct:!0},{text:"The process model",correct:!1},{text:"The major risks",correct:!1},{text:"The people in the development team",correct:!1}]},{question:"During Feasibility, a high-level investigation is carried out. Typically, at this stage, there are a:",answers:[{text:"Small number of requirements",correct:!0},{text:"Large number of conflicting requirements",correct:!1},{text:"Few requirements which can be fully managed",correct:!1},{text:"Number of features which can safely be left out of this project",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM's approach to project management fixes which of the following?",answers:[{text:"Scope, quality and risk at the Foundations phase",correct:!1},{text:"Time, cost and quality at the Foundations phase",correct:!0},{text:"Features with all other functions being used as variables",correct:!1},{text:"Time, cost and quality at the Deployment phase",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM can also incorporate other agile delivery approaches, such as extreme Programming (XP)    and SCRUM to provide the necessary agile management framework to:",answers:[{text:"Enable controlled delivery of agile projects",correct:!0},{text:"Facilitate good practice project management",correct:!1},{text:"Provide adequate techniques for all projects",correct:!1},{text:"Ensure all projects are delivered to time and cost",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of the following statements is true about AgilePM team members?",answers:[{text:"They do not need to be effective communicators",correct:!1},{text:"They must all be like-minded people",correct:!1},{text:"They should be part of a large team to allow for illness",correct:!1},{text:"They must be able to communicate effectively",correct:!0}]},{question:"The solution will be delivered ________, according to the priorities set by the business",answers:[{text:"to the proposed cost",correct:!1},{text:"in total as agreed at the outset",correct:!1},{text:"in the agreed timescale",correct:!0},{text:"within achievable criteria",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM strongly recommends which roles should use collaborative techniques, such as Facilitated Workshops,    for planning?",answers:[{text:"Project Managers and Team Leaders",correct:!0},{text:"Project Managers and Technical Coordinators",correct:!1},{text:"Team Leaders and Business Analysts",correct:!1},{text:"Solution Developers and Business Advisors",correct:!1}]},{question:"Once the project moves into Exploration and Engineering within Development Timeboxes, enough information    will be available to create which of the following?",answers:[{text:"A Feasibility Plan",correct:!1},{text:"The detail of the Deployment Plan",correct:!0},{text:"A Deployment Plan for all products of the project",correct:!1},{text:"Timeboxes for the remainder of the project",correct:!1}]},{question:"The AgilePM framework is supported by a Project Lifecycle (Process) with which of the following?",answers:[{text:"Defined Products, Roles and Responsibilities and recommended Techniques",correct:!0},{text:"A defined process model requiring the use of all processes",correct:!1},{text:"Allowances for the Project Manager to take command of the development team when required",correct:!1},{text:"A set of best practice techniques which permit full testing of each product before deployment",correct:!1}]},{question:"Following the wrong or inappropriate approach to project management can do which of the following?",answers:[{text:"Provide the project management team with invaluable experience",correct:!1},{text:"Encourage the project sponsor to be involved in the development team",correct:!1},{text:"Improve project performance by a large degree",correct:!1},{text:"Dramatically increase the risks",correct:!0}]},{question:"As each increment is completed:",answers:[{text:"A new schedule of Timeboxes is created for the next increment",correct:!0},{text:"New plans must be created to account for any loss of productivity",correct:!1},{text:"A new increment schedule is created for the next deployment",correct:!1},{text:"The development team will gather a new set of requirements from the customer",correct:!1}]},{question:"How does an AgilePM project view having a fixed deadline?",answers:[{text:"As a problem to be overcome",correct:!1},{text:"As a risk that threatens quality",correct:!1},{text:"As a benefit rather than a risk",correct:!0},{text:"As a challenge which may be met",correct:!1}]},{question:"At what point in the project must the stakeholders be prepared to accept that change is inevitable?",answers:[{text:"Each time the customer changes their mind about what is required",correct:!1},{text:"Whenever there is an easier solution which can be developed",correct:!1},{text:"As they understand more about the solution being developed",correct:!0},{text:"When testing demonstrates that the product is unsuitable for use",correct:!1}]},{question:"The stakeholders must be prepared to deliver a:",answers:[{text:"Quality product",correct:!1},{text:"Solution which will maximise business benefits",correct:!1},{text:"Product which meets all the required attributes",correct:!1},{text:"Fit-for-purpose solution",correct:!0}]},{question:"The AgilePM evolutionary approach to planning avoids which problem?",answers:[{text:"Generating an overemphasis on the planning protocol",correct:!1},{text:"Providing a false sense of security for future steps that are still unclear.",correct:!0},{text:"Reliance on success-based planning",correct:!1},{text:"Commitment to activities which cannot be understood until they are finished",correct:!1}]},{question:"There will be no need for complex and bureaucratic monitoring systems in a small AgilePM team working with:",answers:[{text:"III defined objectives to permit them freedom of expression",correct:!1},{text:"Enough resources of time and cost to complete everything assigned to them",correct:!1},{text:"The command and control approach of the Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"Clear objectives in Development Timeboxes of short duration",correct:!0}]},{question:"Adopting a traditional approach where a project must deliver on a fixed date:",answers:[{text:"Reduces risk to meeting the delivery date",correct:!1},{text:"Improves the prospect of the project being able to deliver to cost",correct:!1},{text:"Removes all risk from the project",correct:!1},{text:"Adds a risk since a traditional approach expects to use time as contingency",correct:!0}]},{question:"All people involved with the project work ________ to deliver the optimum solution",answers:[{text:"collectively",correct:!1},{text:"independently",correct:!1},{text:"interactively",correct:!1},{text:"collaboratively",correct:!0}]},{question:"AgilePM should be tailored to suit a project's individual needs within the governance needs set by which    authority?",answers:[{text:"Quality Assurance",correct:!1},{text:"External suppliers",correct:!1},{text:"Regulatory authorities",correct:!1},{text:"The organisation",correct:!0}]},{question:"In AgilePM, plans evolve as the understanding of the:",answers:[{text:"Requirements deepens and the level of uncertainty increases.",correct:!1},{text:"Development team skills becomes clearer",correct:!1},{text:"Complexity of the product being developed increases",correct:!1},{text:"Requirements deepens and the level of uncertainty decreases.",correct:!0}]},{question:"Most projects have 4 parameters - time, cost, features and quality. Trying to fix all these parameters at    the outset is:",answers:[{text:"The mechanism by which AgilePM operates",correct:!1},{text:"Appropriate to most types of projects",correct:!1},{text:"Impractical and is the cause of many common problems",correct:!0},{text:"Difficult to achieve without an experienced Project Manager",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM advocates that projects should do:",answers:[{text:"Only the 'big design up front'",correct:!1},{text:"Possibly 'no design up front'",correct:!1},{text:"Sometimes 'enough design up front'",correct:!1},{text:"Just 'enough design up front'",correct:!0}]},{question:"Managing an AgilePM project is about enabling constant change while:",answers:[{text:"Maintaining business as usual",correct:!1},{text:"Ensuring the customer will fund the changes",correct:!1},{text:"Continuously correcting the course of the project",correct:!0},{text:"Relaxing quality to compensate",correct:!1}]},{question:"The AgilePM framework details which of the following to guide practitioners in the adoption of the    Philosophy?",answers:[{text:"Seven roles which must all be allocated on a one-to-one basis",correct:!1},{text:"Eight working Principles",correct:!0},{text:"Nine techniques which may be omitted as necessary",correct:!1},{text:"Eight Processes which form a process model",correct:!1}]},{question:"How does an AgilePM project react when the business changes its mind?",answers:[{text:"Resists the change",correct:!1},{text:"Sees it as a fact of life",correct:!0},{text:"Adopts the change if it is easy to accommodate",correct:!1},{text:"Re-starts the project with new Terms of Reference (ToR)",correct:!1}]},{question:"Using AgilePM ensures ________ of a fit-for-purpose solution",answers:[{text:"an expensive delivery",correct:!1},{text:"on-time delivery",correct:!0},{text:"the users can specify what they want",correct:!1},{text:"the business will never take delivery",correct:!1}]},{question:"The eight principles of AgilePM support the:",answers:[{text:"Project Management Philosophy",correct:!0},{text:"Process model",correct:!1},{text:"Approach to risk",correct:!1},{text:"Achievement of quality",correct:!1}]},{question:"If a team doesn't follow all the principles what will not be achieved?",answers:[{text:"The project outcome",correct:!1},{text:"A reliable development team",correct:!1},{text:"Business involvement",correct:!1},{text:"The full benefit",correct:!0}]},{question:"'Build incrementally from firm foundations' is an AgilePM principle which is supported when the team do    which of the following?",answers:[{text:"Formally re-assess priorities with each delivered increment",correct:!0},{text:"Informally re-assess priorities with each delivered increment",correct:!1},{text:"Ensure all deployed features provide a return on investment within a month of use",correct:!1},{text:"Build from a 'big design up front'",correct:!1}]},{question:"The 'Deliver on time' principle enables organisations to achieve which of the following?",answers:[{text:"Market opportunities or windows of opportunity",correct:!1},{text:"Market opportunities or legal deadlines",correct:!0},{text:"Maximum return on investment or profit",correct:!1},{text:"No discernible business improvement",correct:!1}]},{question:"In AgilePM, the level of quality to be delivered should be agreed at the start. A solution has to be:",answers:[{text:"Perfect",correct:!1},{text:"As good as it can be",correct:!1},{text:"Good enough",correct:!0},{text:"The best possible option",correct:!1}]},{question:"Ensuring that the members of the team are empowered to take decisions on behalf of those they represent    means that AgilePM teams will be following what principle?",answers:[{text:"Deliver on time",correct:!1},{text:"Focus on the business need",correct:!1},{text:"Collaborate",correct:!0},{text:"Communicate continuously and clearly",correct:!1}]},{question:"Poor communication is often cited as the:",answers:[{text:"Reason why projects succeed",correct:!1},{text:"Biggest single cause of project failure",correct:!0},{text:"Essential ingredient for all projects",correct:!1},{text:"The only cause of projects failing to deliver on time",correct:!1}]},{question:"When AgilePM advocates a pragmatic approach to change what principle is behind the statement?",answers:[{text:"Demonstrate control",correct:!1},{text:"Develop Iteratively",correct:!0},{text:"Focus on the business need",correct:!1},{text:"Communicate continuously and clearly",correct:!1}]},{question:"In AgilePM, the level of ________ should be agreed at the start",answers:[{text:"resources to be consumed",correct:!1},{text:"risk to be taken",correct:!1},{text:"quality to be delivered",correct:!0},{text:"management intervention",correct:!1}]},{question:"Compromising any principle undermines:",answers:[{text:"Risk management",correct:!1},{text:"Timely delivery",correct:!1},{text:"AgilePM's basic philosophy",correct:!0},{text:"The cost of the project",correct:!1}]},{question:"To contribute to the AgilePM principle, never compromise quality, everything is tested:",answers:[{text:"When the team has completed work on the feature",correct:!1},{text:"Before work moves from design to manufacture",correct:!1},{text:"Within the deployment phase",correct:!1},{text:"As early as possible",correct:!0}]},{question:"Teams that work in a spirit of active cooperation and commitment will always:",answers:[{text:"Deliver a full solution to time",correct:!1},{text:"Outperform groups of individuals working only in loose association",correct:!0},{text:"Learn more from each other than from other teams",correct:!1},{text:"Work better on successive projects",correct:!1}]},{question:"When AgilePM advocates first understanding the scope of the business problem to be solved and the proposed    solution, but not in such detail that the project becomes paralysed what principle is being advocated?",answers:[{text:"Build incrementally from firm foundations",correct:!0},{text:"Develop Iteratively",correct:!1},{text:"Focus on the business need",correct:!1},{text:"Demonstrate control",correct:!1}]},{question:"In order to converge on an accurate business solution AgilePM uses:",answers:[{text:"  Iterative development to deliver the right solution ",correct:!0},{text:"  A refined process model for use on all projects",correct:!1},{text:"  Incremental delivery to improve project performance ",correct:!1},{text:"  A fully experienced delivery team",correct:!1}]},{question:"If the AgilePM team is to ensure that the principle 'Communicate continuously and clearly' is practiced which of the following activities will it need to undertake?",answers:[{text:"  Communicate informally regularly and frequently during the working day ",correct:!1},{text:"  Produce full reports and attend frequent meetings",correct:!1},{text:"  Run daily team stand-up sessions and use facilitated workshops ",correct:!0},{text:"  Ensure that every action is documented and approved",correct:!1}]},{question:"Compromising any of the principles undermines AgilePM's philosophy, as together they:",answers:[{text:"  Guarantee a successful project output",correct:!1},{text:"  Contribute essential attributes to all the delivery team members",correct:!1},{text:"  Create an environment which enables the Project Manager to be part time ",correct:!1},{text:"  Deliver a collective value that outweighs their individual benefits",correct:!0}]},{question:"The preparation of the Management Foundations and Timebox Plans are designed to assist the Project Manager and the AgilePM team to follow what principle?",answers:[{text:"  Communicate continuously and clearly ",correct:!1},{text:"  Focus on the business need",correct:!1},{text:"  Never compromise quality ",correct:!1},{text:"  Demonstrate control",correct:!0}]},{question:"The Business Analyst is responsible for facilitating a high level of ________ between team members ",answers:[{text:"  involvement",correct:!1},{text:"  collaboration ",correct:!0},{text:"  input",correct:!1},{text:"  delegation",correct:!1}]},{question:"The principles direct the team in the attitude they must take and the:",answers:[{text:"  Approach they must take to collaboration",correct:!1},{text:"  Mindset they must adopt in order to deliver consistently ",correct:!0},{text:"  Establishment of the timeboxing periods",correct:!1},{text:"  Governance procedures for the project management team",correct:!1}]},{question:"In support of the AgilePM principle, collaborate, the Business Visionary, Business Ambassador and Business Advisor roles:",answers:[{text:"  Are optional and can be deleted without compromising quality",correct:!1},{text:"  Define and develop the product to meet the business needs of the business sponsor",correct:!1},{text:"  Bring the appropriate subject matter experts into the project so they can contribute to the solution",correct:!0},{text:"  Hold the Project Manager accountable for the work of the development team(s)",correct:!1}]},{question:"An AgilePM team needs to be ________ when monitoring and controlling progress ",answers:[{text:"  proactive",correct:!0},{text:"  reactive",correct:!1},{text:"  pragmatic",correct:!1},{text:"  adventurous",correct:!1}]},{question:"The 'Collaborate' principle is worked out in an AgilePM project when which of the following is happening?",answers:[{text:"  Project Managers organise teams according to a master project plan",correct:!1},{text:"  All members of the project team involve themselves in every step of development",correct:!1},{text:"  Members of the team are empowered to take decisions on behalf of those they represent ",correct:!0},{text:"  No-one needs to ask anything because they are provided with full details of all they have to do",correct:!1}]},{question:"Delivering products on time is a very desirable outcome for a project and is:",answers:[{text:"  Quite often the single most important success factor ",correct:!0},{text:"  Absolutely essential for success",correct:!1},{text:"  Likely to take second place to delivery to scope ",correct:!1},{text:"  The only criteria that matters",correct:!1}]},{question:"Develop 'Iteratively' is one of the AgilePM principles which is supported when which of the following actions is taken by the team?",answers:[{text:"  Ensure the team deploys the longest iteration cycles possible ",correct:!1},{text:"  Build customer feedback into each iteration",correct:!0},{text:"  Create a physical prototype for every feature to aid development ",correct:!1},{text:"  Build supplier feedback into each iteration",correct:!1}]},{question:"In order to deliver real business benefit early, AgilePM advocates:",answers:[{text:"  Iterative development",correct:!1},{text:"  A co-located delivery team",correct:!1},{text:"  At team that is as large as possible ",correct:!1},{text:"  Incremental delivery",correct:!0}]},{question:"If the business agrees that the features in the minimum usable subset have been provided adequately, then the solution should be acceptable' is a definition of what AgilePM principle? ",answers:[{text:"  Focus on the business need",correct:!1},{text:"  Communicate continuously and clearly",correct:!1},{text:"  Demonstrate control",correct:!1},{text:"  Never compromise quality",correct:!0}]},{question:"The collective value of AgilePM's principles enables organisations to do which of the following?",answers:[{text:"  Deliver best value business solutions collaboratively ",correct:!0},{text:"  Trust its project team to work independently",correct:!1},{text:"  Achieve the best return on investment ",correct:!1},{text:"  Micromanage the project at every step",correct:!1}]},{question:"It is essential to be in control of a project:",answers:[{text:"  When reports are needed",correct:!1},{text:"  During the start and end of a critical project ",correct:!1},{text:"  At all times",correct:!0},{text:"  As directed by the Project Manager",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM emphasises the value of human interaction through Stand-ups, Facilitated Workshops, clearly defined roles and user involvement. What principle is being described as being fulfilled this way?",answers:[{text:"  Build incrementally from firm foundations ",correct:!1},{text:"  Never compromise quality",correct:!1},{text:"  Communicate continuously and clearly ",correct:!0},{text:"  Demonstrate control",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM advocates a ________ to change that relies on iteration in order to embrace change ",answers:[{text:"  restrained approach",correct:!1},{text:"  bureaucratic approach ",correct:!1},{text:"  business-like approach",correct:!1},{text:"  pragmatic approach",correct:!0}]},{question:"In order to fulfil the principle, deliver on time, AgilePM teams will:",answers:[{text:"  Compromise on quality ",correct:!1},{text:"  Timebox the work",correct:!0},{text:"  Treat cost as a variable",correct:!1},{text:"  Off-set any overruns by using overtime",correct:!1}]},{question:"It is important to remember that a project is:",answers:[{text:"  A means to an end, not an end in itself ",correct:!0},{text:"  Self-serving",correct:!1},{text:"  To be treated as only a mechanism for delivering a business product ",correct:!1},{text:"  The most significant part of business as usual",correct:!1}]},{question:"To practice the principle 'Focus on the business need' means the team will do which of the following?",answers:[{text:"  Guarantee the Minimum Usable Subset",correct:!0},{text:"  Deliver to the full specification agreed up front",correct:!1},{text:"  Produce a valuable product which may require more time to complete",correct:!1},{text:"  Consult with the sponsor at each development step to ensure compliance",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of the following should an AgilePM team do if they are upholding the 'Never compromise quality' principle?",answers:[{text:"  Only attempt what can be achieved in the limited time available",correct:!1},{text:"  Provide the customer with a statement of what has been done during deployment ",correct:!1},{text:"  Use only top level components to develop the product",correct:!1},{text:"  Design, document and test appropriately",correct:!0}]},{question:"Techniques such as Timeboxing and MoSCoW Prioritisation enable AgilePM teams to implement what principle?",answers:[{text:"  Build incrementally from firm foundations ",correct:!1},{text:"  Deliver on time",correct:!0},{text:"  Develop Iteratively",correct:!1},{text:"  Focus on the business need",correct:!1}]},{question:"If an AgilePM team is seeking continuous business sponsorship and commitment which principle is it upholding?",answers:[{text:"  Focus on the business need",correct:!0},{text:"  Never compromise quality",correct:!1},{text:"  Communicate continuously and clearly",correct:!1},{text:"  Demonstrate control",correct:!1}]},{question:"Managing proactively is one way of ensuring that control is demonstrated. Which of the following is another way of upholding that principle?",answers:[{text:"  Involve every team member in developing the project plan ",correct:!1},{text:"  Measure progress through a focus on completed activities ",correct:!1},{text:"  Providing the customer with regular and routine reports",correct:!1},{text:"  Make plans and progress visible to all",correct:!0}]},{question:"When AgilePM advocates a pragmatic approach to change what principle is behind the statement?",answers:[{text:"  Demonstrate control ",correct:!1},{text:"  Develop Iteratively",correct:!0},{text:"  Focus on the business need",correct:!1},{text:"  Communicate continuously and clearly",correct:!1}]},{question:"In line with the fifth and sixth principles, the AgilePM lifecycle is both:",answers:[{text:"  Iterative and incremental",correct:!0},{text:"  Developmental and worthwhile ",correct:!1},{text:"  Iterative and integrative",correct:!1},{text:"  Process driven and incremental",correct:!1}]},{question:"The AgilePM lifecycle can be configured for:",answers:[{text:"  Risky projects",correct:!1},{text:"  Hardware projects ",correct:!1},{text:"  Small projects",correct:!0},{text:"  Software projects",correct:!1}]},{question:"Once the lifecycle has been configured, the team structures have been refined and key products given more emphasis is it appropriate in larger projects to introduce additional management products?",answers:[{text:"  No, because AgilePM restricts management products to those it defines ",correct:!1},{text:"  Yes, because they would inappropriate for smaller projects",correct:!0},{text:"  No, because they would need to be developed using the Engineering phase",correct:!1},{text:"  Yes, because corporate management has the right to impose any necessary management product",correct:!1}]},{question:"What AgilePM phase has the objective of expanding and refining any products required to successfully operate and support the solution in live operation?",answers:[{text:"  Engineering ",correct:!0},{text:"  Exploration ",correct:!1},{text:"  Deployment ",correct:!1},{text:"  Foundations",correct:!1}]},{question:"Increments are in turn divided into:",answers:[{text:"  Iteration phases",correct:!1},{text:"  Development Timeboxes ",correct:!0},{text:"  Deployed features",correct:!1},{text:"  Daily Stand-Ups",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM provides what type of framework consisting of seven lifecycle phases?",answers:[{text:"  Fixed and repetitive",correct:!1},{text:"  Open and challenging ",correct:!1},{text:"  Iterative and definitive",correct:!1},{text:"  Iterative and incremental",correct:!0}]},{question:"The project / programme characteristics must be taken into consideration in order to configure the optimum lifecycle for delivery of:",answers:[{text:"  The Minimum Usable Subset",correct:!1},{text:"  The most advanced product possible",correct:!1},{text:"  User training and maintenance support",correct:!1},{text:"  Early business benefit and risk mitigation",correct:!0}]},{question:"What phase in the AgilePM lifecycle has an objective of baselining the high-level requirements for the project and describing their priority and relevance to the business need? ",answers:[{text:" Pre-Project",correct:!1},{text:" Engineering ",correct:!1},{text:" Deployment ",correct:!1},{text:" Foundations",correct:!0}]},{question:"The project / programme characteristics must be taken into consideration in order to configure the ________ early business benefit and risk mitigation",answers:[{text:"  best option for the production of",correct:!1},{text:"  ultimate product for the recovery of",correct:!1},{text:"  development management team for the recovery of ",correct:!1},{text:"  optimum lifecycle for delivery of",correct:!0}]},{question:"The primary purpose of the Deployment phase is to:",answers:[{text:"  Refine the specification for the solution",correct:!1},{text:"  Deliver the proposed return on investment ",correct:!1},{text:"  Get the solution into live / production use",correct:!0},{text:"  Test the product before the Engineering phase can be completed",correct:!1}]},{question:"If there is a need to generate versions of the full solution as early as possible in order to prove viability of the solution and/or properly plan for deployment which aspect of configuring the Lifecycle may be useful?",answers:[{text:"  Using very short Timeboxes with unlimited resources",correct:!1},{text:"  Deploying each feature as developed to gain early user feedback",correct:!1},{text:"  Separating the project into two work streams with two Project Managers",correct:!1},{text:"  The use of multiple teams with Exploration and Engineering work split between them",correct:!0}]},{question:"The work of the pre-project phase simply formalises a proposal for a project and places it:",answers:[{text:"  In a ranked priority against business as usual work",correct:!1},{text:"  In the context of other potential work to be carried out by the organisation",correct:!0},{text:"  In a backlog of work to be done when development teams have completed their current workload",correct:!1},{text:"  Alongside other work to be undertaken so that resources can be assigned on a 'must needs' basis",correct:!1}]},{question:"The focus of a Development Timebox may reflect:",answers:[{text:"  A single development phase ",correct:!0},{text:"  Multiple projects",correct:!1},{text:"  The development of at least two 'must have' features ",correct:!1},{text:"  The development of the project plan",correct:!1}]},{question:"The primary purpose of what AgilePM lifecycle phase is to get the solution into live use?",answers:[{text:"  Post-Project phase ",correct:!1},{text:"  Deployment phase ",correct:!0},{text:"  Engineering phase ",correct:!1},{text:"  Pre-Project phase",correct:!1}]},{question:"Scalability is a:",answers:[{text:"  Significant problem for the lifecycle ",correct:!1},{text:"  Key attribute of AgilePM",correct:!0},{text:"  Function which should not be used",correct:!1},{text:"  Primary capability which must always be employed",correct:!1}]},{question:"Combining Exploration and Engineering work to deliver fully engineered subsets of the end product in a single pass is recommended for which of the following reasons?",answers:[{text:"  The preference of the Project Manager   ",correct:!1},{text:"  The project is too small to warrant separation of the phases",correct:!0},{text:"  The architectural risk associated with development is very high ",correct:!1},{text:"  The solution is too complex to separate the two phase",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Exploration phase is used to iteratively and incrementally investigate detailed business requirements and:",answers:[{text:"  Translate them into a viable solution",correct:!0},{text:"  Turn the prototype into a workable solution",correct:!1},{text:"  Handle all deployment options for return on investment",correct:!1},{text:"  Hand over to the Engineering phase to produce a full specification for further development",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which is an objective of the Pre-Project phase?",answers:[{text:"  To propose a full list of deliverables",correct:!1},{text:"  To identify a Business Sponsor and Business Visionary",correct:!0},{text:"  To confirm that the business strategy is in line with the project ",correct:!1},{text:"  To appoint the full development team",correct:!1}]},{question:"The end-product of what phase in the AgilePM lifecycle will be refined further during the Engineering phase to ensure technical acceptance criteria such as performance, capacity, security, supportability and maintainability are met?",answers:[{text:"  Engineering ",correct:!1},{text:"  Post-Project ",correct:!1},{text:"  Deployment ",correct:!1},{text:"  Exploration",correct:!0}]},{question:"The ________ enables agreement that the project can move safely from one lifecycle phase to another",answers:[{text:"  acceptance of products ",correct:!0},{text:"  deployment of features ",correct:!1},{text:"  approval of reports",correct:!1},{text:"  certification of quality",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Post-Project phase takes place after the last planned deployment of the solution and its purpose is to reflect on the performance of the project in terms of the:",answers:[{text:"  Uptime of the product in production use",correct:!1},{text:"  Proposed lifetime of the solution",correct:!1},{text:"  Ability of the users to operate the product delivered ",correct:!1},{text:"  Business value actually achieved",correct:!0}]},{question:"When the project is within the environment of a large business organisation it is important that it recognises and works with which of the following?",answers:[{text:"  Local recommendations",correct:!1},{text:"  Business as usual practices ",correct:!1},{text:"  Corporate governance",correct:!0},{text:"  Tight timelines",correct:!1}]},{question:"If a project is assessed to be simple, low-risk and of short duration which of the following options correctly represents how the Lifecycle may be used?",answers:[{text:"  The Feasibility phase and the Foundations phase must be used in sequence ",correct:!1},{text:"  The Feasibility phase may be omitted",correct:!1},{text:"  The Foundations phase may be omitted",correct:!1},{text:"  The Feasibility phase and the Foundations phase may be combined",correct:!0}]},{question:"To assess whether the benefits described in the Business Case have actually been achieved is the objective of what AgilePM phase?",answers:[{text:"  Deployment ",correct:!1},{text:"  Pre-Project ",correct:!1},{text:"  Post-Project ",correct:!0},{text:"  Exploration",correct:!1}]},{question:"Once the lifecycle has been configured, the team structures can be refined:",answers:[{text:"  To support multiple teams",correct:!0},{text:"  In support of corporate management requirements ",correct:!1},{text:"  In line with strategic objectives",correct:!1},{text:"  To accommodate situations where there is no Project Manager",correct:!1}]},{question:"What phase in the AgilePM lifecycle provides the first opportunity for deciding whether a proposed project is viable from both a business and a technical perspective?",answers:[{text:"  Deployment ",correct:!1},{text:"  Foundations ",correct:!1},{text:"  Feasibility",correct:!0},{text:"  Post-Project",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM recognises the need for which of the following whilst acknowledging and accepting the advantages and constraints of working in a substantial corporate environment?",answers:[{text:"  Rigidity",correct:!1},{text:"  Flexibility ",correct:!1},{text:"  Agility",correct:!0},{text:"  Accountability",correct:!1}]},{question:"Development effort in the Engineering phase is focused primarily on addressing:",answers:[{text:"  Functional requirements",correct:!1},{text:"  Non-functional requirements ",correct:!0},{text:"  Final features",correct:!1},{text:"  What high level features will be left out of the deployed solution",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which statement correctly expresses the possibility for using more than one development team?",answers:[{text:"  One team may concentrate on exploratory work and the other on engineering work ",correct:!0},{text:"  The AgilePM Lifecycle is not configurable for multiple teams",correct:!1},{text:"  For AgilePM to be successful there must always be at least three development teams within the project",correct:!1},{text:"  The deliverable solution will be compromised if two teams undertake different parts of the",correct:!1}]},{question:"Lifecycle",answers:[{text:"  feature developers",correct:!1},{text:"  business representatives ",correct:!0},{text:"  the Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"  potential users",correct:!1}]},{question:"The iterative nature of AgilePM enables ________ to see work under construction, comment on it and request changes during the development of an increment of the solution",answers:[{text:"  7",correct:!0},{text:"  5",correct:!1},{text:"  8",correct:!1},{text:"  2",correct:!1}]},{question:"How many phases does AgilePM propose?",answers:[{text:"  Engineering phase ",correct:!1},{text:"  Deployment",correct:!1},{text:"  Development Timebox ",correct:!0},{text:"  Features development",correct:!1}]},{question:"What does AgilePM say should provide a focus for a single development phase?",answers:[{text:"  Small projects to large enterprise-wide programmes",correct:!0},{text:"  Information technology projects only regardless of size",correct:!1},{text:"  Any project which does not include any information technology products ",correct:!1},{text:"  Projects where time can be used as contingency",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of the following statements correctly represents the possibilities for configuring the AgilePM lifecycle?",answers:[{text:"  A Deployment phase followed by a Post-Project phase ",correct:!1},{text:"  An Exploration phase followed by an Engineering phase ",correct:!1},{text:"  A Feasibility phase followed by a Foundations phase",correct:!0},{text:"  A Foundations phase followed by an Engineering phase",correct:!1}]},{question:"Once the Pre-Project activity has been completed, typically AgilePM projects begin with:",answers:[{text:"  Engineering of the product into a workable solution ",correct:!1},{text:"  Post-Project evaluation of the benefits",correct:!1},{text:"  Pre-Project instruction to commence another project",correct:!1},{text:"  Deployment of a working solution into the live environment",correct:!0}]},{question:"Actual development work is divided into one or more increments, which normally end with the:",answers:[{text:"  If the organisation should require a project to be started",correct:!1},{text:"  On the detailed costs for the delivery of the solution to the business problem ",correct:!1},{text:"  Whether a proposed project is viable",correct:!0},{text:"  When the deployments will be made",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Feasibility phase provides the first opportunity for deciding:",answers:[{text:"  The maximum possible governance",correct:!1},{text:"  An AgilePM Lifecycle that ensures on time delivery",correct:!1},{text:"  All the skills necessary for operating the deployed solution ",correct:!1},{text:"  A clear project focus that is both robust and flexible",correct:!0}]},{question:"In establishing the foundations, the 3 essential perspectives of business, solution and management need to be combined to provide:",answers:[{text:"  A risk to the AgilePM approach ",correct:!0},{text:"  The best chance of success",correct:!1},{text:"  An unacceptable business case",correct:!1},{text:"  An opportunity for the development team to be creative",correct:!1}]},{question:"If instrumental success factors (ICFs) of AgilePM projects cannot be met, this presents:",answers:[{text:"  The next Engineering phase ",correct:!1},{text:"  Operational use",correct:!0},{text:"  Final test",correct:!1},{text:"  The hands of users for training",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Deployment phase places the solution created in an increment into:",answers:[{text:"  Regulatory approval",correct:!1},{text:"  Technical Architecture ",correct:!1},{text:"  Product testing",correct:!1},{text:"  Business as usual",correct:!0}]},{question:"The Business Area Definition (BAD) should be created for any project where the proposed solution impacts on which of the following?",answers:[{text:"  Business rationale for the programme ",correct:!1},{text:"  AgilePM philosophy",correct:!0},{text:"  AgilePM Lifecycle",correct:!1},{text:"  Delivery of the full product as the only option",correct:!1}]},{question:"It is important that the Business Sponsor / senior management understands and accepts the:",answers:[{text:"  Project Manager as part of the Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Advisor and Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Ambassador(s) in the Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!0},{text:"  Whole Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!1}]},{question:"The senior business management must agree to delegate decision-making to the:",answers:[{text:"  Foundations ",correct:!1},{text:"  Post-Project ",correct:!1},{text:"  Engineering ",correct:!1},{text:"  Pre-Project",correct:!0}]},{question:"What AgilePM phase has the objective of scoping, planning and resourcing the Feasibility phase?",answers:[{text:"  Project Plan ",correct:!1},{text:"  Outline Plan ",correct:!0},{text:"  Timebox Plan",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Approach Questionnaire (PAQ)",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Delivery Plan refines and elaborates on the schedule described in which other management product?",answers:[{text:"  Feasibility",correct:!0},{text:"  Foundations ",correct:!1},{text:"  Exploration ",correct:!1},{text:"  Engineering",correct:!1}]},{question:"What AgilePM Lifecycle phase is used to describe the organisation and governance aspects of the project?",answers:[{text:"  instructions to the project team",correct:!1},{text:"  all updated plans",correct:!1},{text:"  reports, documents and logs",correct:!0},{text:"  information from external sources",correct:!1}]},{question:"To achieve an early return on investment, the organisation needs to be amenable to the:\n",answers:[{text:"  Incremental delivery of solutions",correct:!0},{text:"  Easiest features being developed first of all",correct:!1},{text:"  Whole solution being engineered in one iteration",correct:!1},{text:"  Financial Advisor being instrumental in product development",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM identifies deliverables associated with each phase of the lifecycle. These are referred to as:",answers:[{text:"  Solutions ",correct:!1},{text:"  Outcomes ",correct:!1},{text:"  Benefits",correct:!1},{text:"  Products",correct:!0}]},{question:"To improve the performance of the Solution Development Team (SDT) specialists may be called in as long as the:",answers:[{text:"  Project Manager does not change ",correct:!1},{text:"  Core team remains stable",correct:!0},{text:"  Risk is acceptable",correct:!1},{text:"  Team does not have more than ten members",correct:!1}]},{question:"When necessary, which phase will be used to evolve the Business Area Definition (BAD) and System Architecture Definition (SAD) products into models that describe how the solution works and how it supports all impacted business processes and systems?",answers:[{text:"  Foundations ",correct:!1},{text:"  Deployment ",correct:!1},{text:"  Exploration ",correct:!0},{text:"  Post-Project",correct:!1}]},{question:"The formal product definitions are:",answers:[{text:"  Strategic ",correct:!1},{text:"  Generic",correct:!0},{text:"  Templates ",correct:!1},{text:"  Definitive",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Outline Plan is refined and replaced by the Delivery Plan for the project which in turn is refined to create the individual:",answers:[{text:"  Delivery Plans",correct:!1},{text:"  Phase plans",correct:!1},{text:"  Timebox Plans",correct:!0},{text:"  Integration Timeboxes",correct:!1}]},{question:"For which AgilePM Lifecycle phase is it a precondition that the Evolving Solution from the    Exploration phase has been approved?",answers:[{text:"  Deployment ",correct:!1},{text:"  Foundations ",correct:!1},{text:"  Pre-Project ",correct:!1},{text:"  Engineering",correct:!0}]},{question:"AgilePM teams rely on rich communication as their first choice. For this to be effective what is the optimum size of Solution Development Team (SDT) suggested by AgilePM?",answers:[{text:"  No more than fifteen and not less than twelve ",correct:!1},{text:"  At least six",correct:!1},{text:"  Three groups of seven ",correct:!1},{text:"  Five to nine",correct:!0}]},{question:"The primary aim of the Terms of Reference (ToR) is to:",answers:[{text:"  Scope and justify the feasibility investigation ",correct:!0},{text:"  Define the solution to be developed",correct:!1},{text:"  Propose how only the Post-Project phase will be undertaken ",correct:!1},{text:"  Refine the makeup of the Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!1}]},{question:"What is the name of the simple management product AgilePM provides that helps to identify and confirm the level of achievement of all the relevant factors and to assess potential risk areas to be addressed?",answers:[{text:"  Project Approach Questionnaire",correct:!0},{text:"  Programme Approach Questionnaire ",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Plan",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Awareness Questionnaire",correct:!1}]},{question:"The number of passes through the Deployment phase will depend on whether it is sensible and feasible for the ________ to accept delivery of the overall solution incrementally",answers:[{text:"  business",correct:!0},{text:"  Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!1},{text:"  Technical Architect ",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Sponsor",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM integrates a project management lifecycle and a product development lifecycle into a:",answers:[{text:"  Simple framework ",correct:!1},{text:"  Single framework",correct:!0},{text:"  Single project management method",correct:!1},{text:"  Framework which needs no modification",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Outline plan provides an overview of the project from a Project Management and:",answers:[{text:"  The corporate point of view ",correct:!1},{text:"  Benefits recovery viewpoint ",correct:!1},{text:"  Product testing",correct:!1},{text:"  Solution Delivery perspective",correct:!0}]},{question:"If having a common understanding of what needs to be in place is a good starting point for any project then agreeing what else increases the likelihood of a successful AgilePM project?",answers:[{text:"  The specification of the solution to be developed",correct:!1},{text:"  The optimum starting position for an AgilePM project",correct:!0},{text:"  The characteristics of the Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!1},{text:"  The degree to which cost and quality can be used to off-set variances in time",correct:!1}]},{question:"If a Solution Development Team (SDT) with diverse skills is to function as a coherent unit what capability should all team members have?",answers:[{text:"  Expert technical knowledge of the solution being developed ",correct:!1},{text:"  Management experience",correct:!1},{text:"  Good communication skills",correct:!0},{text:"  Knowledge of the regulatory requirements which have to be met",correct:!1}]},{question:"For most organisations, AgilePM is all that is needed, although some gain value from integrating AgilePM with project management methods, such as:",answers:[{text:"  Programme management",correct:!1},{text:"  Business as usual ",correct:!1},{text:"  PRINCE2 and PMI",correct:!0},{text:"  Corporate strategic development approach",correct:!1}]},{question:"When the Business Vision has been evolved from the Feasibility Assessment which of the following should it clearly describe?",answers:[{text:"  The business as it will be after each iteration",correct:!1},{text:"  How the big picture differs from the current reality ",correct:!0},{text:"  Who will be the Business Ambassador",correct:!1},{text:"  The responsibilities of the Project Manager",correct:!1}]},{question:"In order to deliver the right thing at the right time and handle change dynamically which of the following statement represents what needs to be agreed by all parties?",answers:[{text:"  The project may deliver more than 100% of the possible solution",correct:!1},{text:"  The project may not deliver less than 100% of the possible solution ",correct:!1},{text:"  The project will deliver 100% of the possible solution",correct:!1},{text:"  The project may deliver less than 100% of the possible solution",correct:!0}]},{question:"During the Exploration phase, all or part of the problem or opportunity is investigated:",answers:[{text:"  And a partial solution is created",correct:!0},{text:"  But only a detailed specification will be produced ",correct:!1},{text:"  Together with a full set of test protocols",correct:!1},{text:"  And the full solution developed to production standard",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Prioritised Requirements List (PRL) describes, at a high level, which of the following?",answers:[{text:"  The requirements which can safely be left out of the delivered solution",correct:!1},{text:"  A breakdown of the detail of the cost and time to deliver the required features",correct:!1},{text:"  The requirements that the project needs to address if the Business Case is to be met ",correct:!0},{text:"  A list of the features which the suppliers believe they can deliver",correct:!1}]},{question:"Where a decision is ________ the agreed boundaries this would still need to be formally escalated",answers:[{text:"  outside ",correct:!0},{text:"  inside",correct:!1},{text:"  within",correct:!1},{text:"  at the level of",correct:!1}]},{question:"What happens after the project has delivered the solution to the business problem or opportunity?",answers:[{text:"  The next Timebox comes into play",correct:!1},{text:"  The project team is retained for maintenance purposes",correct:!1},{text:"  The project team is disbanded and the Post-Project phase comes into play ",correct:!0},{text:"  Nothing further needs to happen",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Solution Prototype may be which of the following?",answers:[{text:"  Disposable ",correct:!0},{text:"  Enduring",correct:!1},{text:"  Inaccurate",correct:!1},{text:"  Deployable",correct:!1}]},{question:"The level of business commitment for this project should be:",answers:[{text:"  Left to the discretion of the Project Manager ",correct:!1},{text:"  Minimal to prevent micromanagement",correct:!1},{text:"  Set at the optimum level for full benefits recovery ",correct:!1},{text:"  Quantified and discussed in the early stages",correct:!0}]},{question:"Detailing the Business Case for the project is an aspect of the work of what phase of the AgilePM Lifecycle?",answers:[{text:"  Pre-Project ",correct:!1},{text:"  Foundations ",correct:!0},{text:"  Feasibility",correct:!1},{text:"  Deployment",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Pareto Principle (or 80:20 rule) implies that it is possible that ________ might be enabled by an early interim delivery",answers:[{text:"  all the proposed benefit ",correct:!1},{text:"  some of the users",correct:!1},{text:"  none of the risks",correct:!1},{text:"  the vast majority of the benefit",correct:!0}]},{question:"The Business Foundations product provides information for and/or about the business that is fundamental to the success of the project and needs to be understood by which of the following?",answers:[{text:"  All project stakeholders",correct:!0},{text:"  The Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!1},{text:"  All Team Leaders across the organisation ",correct:!1},{text:"  The corporate finance team",correct:!1}]},{question:"Choosing AgilePM for a project management method means that the entire project will be driven by which project parameter?",answers:[{text:"  Delivering to full scope",correct:!1},{text:"  Providing a solution which will be of highest quality ",correct:!1},{text:"  Ensuring on-time delivery",correct:!0},{text:"  Developing a solution to the 'can do1 philosophy",correct:!1}]},{question:"Since AgilePM is typically used for creating solutions that are required quickly, Feasibility and Foundations should last no more than:",answers:[{text:"  A few hours",correct:!1},{text:"  A few months",correct:!1},{text:"  Two or three days ",correct:!1},{text:"  A few weeks",correct:!0}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM has Ability to commit appropriate funds and resources?",answers:[{text:"  Teal Leader",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Sponsor",correct:!0},{text:"  Solution Developer ",correct:!1},{text:"  Solution Tester",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM approves changes to the high-level requirements in the Prioritised Requirements List (PRL)?",answers:[{text:"  Teal Leader",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Sponsor ",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Visionary ",correct:!0},{text:"  Business Analyst",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM manages the overall configuration of the project?",answers:[{text:"  Technical Coordinator ",correct:!1},{text:"  Technical Advisor",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Manager ",correct:!0},{text:"  Business Analyst",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM manages business involvement within the Solution Development Teams (SDTs)?",answers:[{text:"  Business Visionary",correct:!1},{text:"  Workshop Facilitator ",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Analyst",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Manager",correct:!0}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM does high-level project planning and scheduling, but not detailed task planning?",answers:[{text:"  Business Visionary",correct:!1},{text:"  DSDM Coach",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Manager ",correct:!0},{text:"  Teal Leader",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM determines the technical environments?",answers:[{text:"  Technical Coordinator ",correct:!0},{text:"  DSDM Coach",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"  Teal Leader",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM resolves technical differences between technical team members?",answers:[{text:"  Technical Advisor",correct:!1},{text:"  Technical Coordinator ",correct:!0},{text:"  Solution Developer",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Ambassador",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM ensures adherence to standards of best practice?",answers:[{text:"  Technical Advisor",correct:!1},{text:"  Solution Developer ",correct:!1},{text:"  Solution Tester",correct:!1},{text:"  Technical Coordinator",correct:!0}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM ensures team functions as a whole and meets objectives?",answers:[{text:"  Technical Advisor ",correct:!1},{text:"  DSDM Coach",correct:!1},{text:"  Team Leader",correct:!0},{text:"  Technical Coordinator",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM provides key input to business requirements and design sessions?",answers:[{text:"  Technical Advisor ",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Visionary ",correct:!1},{text:"  Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Ambassador",correct:!0}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM manages workshop process?",answers:[{text:"  DSDM Coach",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Visionary ",correct:!1},{text:"  Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"  Workshop Facilitator",correct:!0}]},{question:"People working together effectively are the foundation of:",answers:[{text:"  Any successful project ",correct:!0},{text:"  A worthwhile solution",correct:!1},{text:"  Achieving the proposed return on investment ",correct:!1},{text:"  A collaborative development team",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Project Manager role is responsible for:",answers:[{text:"  Developing the solution",correct:!1},{text:"  Giving clear and detailed technical direction to the development team ",correct:!1},{text:"  Designing the test routines for the deliverable solution",correct:!1},{text:"  All aspects of the delivery of the solution",correct:!0}]},{question:"On an AgilePM project team which role is the most senior project-level business role?",answers:[{text:"  The Business Visionary ",correct:!1},{text:"  The Business Sponsor ",correct:!0},{text:"  The Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"  The Technical Coordinator",correct:!1}]},{question:"In the AgilePM team model the Business Sponsor is responsible for which function(s)?",answers:[{text:"  Detailed features requirements setting",correct:!1},{text:"  How the solution will work viewed from the user perspective ",correct:!1},{text:"  Overall strategic direction and funding",correct:!0},{text:"  Design and testing of the solution",correct:!1}]},{question:"The ________ supports the Solution Development Team (SDT) through the provision of detailed and often specialist technical input",answers:[{text:"  Solution Tester ",correct:!1},{text:"  DSDM Coach",correct:!1},{text:"  Line Manager",correct:!1},{text:"  Technical Advisor",correct:!0}]},{question:"Which role in an AgilePM project team is said to provide the glue that holds the project together?",answers:[{text:"  Technical Coordinator ",correct:!0},{text:"  DSDM Coach",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"  Workshop Facilitator",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Business Sponsor must hold a sufficiently high position in the organisation to be able to:",answers:[{text:"  Make business decisions on behalf of the project ",correct:!1},{text:"  Resolve business issues",correct:!0},{text:"  Address all risks facing the project",correct:!1},{text:"  Commit to the Prioritised Requirements List",correct:!1}]},{question:"The ________ ensures that the business needs are properly analysed and are correctly reflected in the guidance the team needs to generate the solution?",answers:[{text:"  Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Sponsor",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Manager ",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Analyst",correct:!0}]},{question:"The Technical Coordinator performs the same function, from a technical perspective, as the Business Visionary does from a:",answers:[{text:"  Business perspective",correct:!0},{text:"  Organisation perspective ",correct:!1},{text:"  Corporate perspective",correct:!1},{text:"  Delivery team perspective",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM assigns clear roles and responsibilities to each person in a project but from which side of the project should such people be recruited to the roles?",answers:[{text:"  Only from the 'customer' side of the project",correct:!1},{text:"  From the 'customer' and 'supplier' side of the project",correct:!0},{text:"  Only 'supplier' sided people are needed for the Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!1},{text:"  Only from the 'business' side of the project",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role is responsible for providing technical advice about the development of support documentation?",answers:[{text:"  Solution Tester",correct:!1},{text:"  Solution Developer ",correct:!1},{text:"  Technical Advisor",correct:!0},{text:"  Team Leader",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Business Ambassador generally comes from:",answers:[{text:"  Anywhere in the business ",correct:!1},{text:"  A financial background",correct:!1},{text:"  The highest level of management within the business ",correct:!1},{text:"  The business area being addressed",correct:!0}]},{question:"The Solution Development Team (SDT) on an AgilePM project is empowered to make decisions on a day-to-day basis:",answers:[{text:"  In consultation with the Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"  Within their agreed Terms of Reference (ToR)",correct:!0},{text:"  Provided they meet all their Timebox objectives ",correct:!1},{text:"  Even if they breach technical requirements",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Solution Tester should be fully integrated with the Solution Development Team (SDT) and tests the solution in accordance with what management product?",answers:[{text:"  Project Plan",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Test Plan",correct:!1},{text:"  Technical Testing Strategy ",correct:!0},{text:"  Generic Testing Protocols",correct:!1}]},{question:"Specialist roles may also need to be involved and brought into the Solution Development Teams (SDTs) on an ad hoc basis by the:",answers:[{text:"  Project Manager or Team Leader",correct:!0},{text:"  Team Leader and Technical Coordinator ",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Sponsor and Project Manager ",correct:!1},{text:"  Anyone with an interest in the project",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role is key to helping a team with limited experience of using AgilePM get the most out of the approach within the context of the wider organisation in which they work?",answers:[{text:"  Team Leader ",correct:!1},{text:"  DSDM Coach",correct:!0},{text:"  Business Visionary",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Manager",correct:!1}]},{question:"It is vital that the Project Manager takes responsibility throughout the duration of the project. This must include:",answers:[{text:"  All technical decisions on the solution architecture",correct:!1},{text:"  Ensuring that all funding is available before any work starts on product development ",correct:!1},{text:"  Coaching sessions for everyone involved with the project",correct:!1},{text:"  Both business and technical delivery aspects of the project",correct:!0}]},{question:"The solution / technical interests are represented by a number of roles. Which of the following roles is one of them?",answers:[{text:"  Solution Tester ",correct:!0},{text:"  Project Manager ",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Advisor ",correct:!1},{text:"  DSDM Coach",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Business Advisor will normally be ________ but may for example, simply provide legal or regulatory advice with which the solution must comply",answers:[{text:"  the detail designer of the solution to be produced",correct:!1},{text:"  someone from the senior management level of the business sponsoring the project ",correct:!1},{text:"  able to fully test the solution for conformity to business needs",correct:!1},{text:"  an intended user or beneficiary of the solution",correct:!0}]},{question:"The Business Sponsor is the:",answers:[{text:"  Project Sponsor",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Champion",correct:!0},{text:"  User group manager ",correct:!1},{text:"  Team Leader",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role in an AgilePM project team is responsible for managing the overall configuration of the project?",answers:[{text:"  Technical Coordinator",correct:!1},{text:"  Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"  Solution Developer ",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Manager",correct:!0}]},{question:"The Development roles are Team Leader, Business Ambassador, Business Analyst, Solution Developer and Solution Tester. AgilePM refers to this team jointly as which of the following?",answers:[{text:"  The 'doers' of the project",correct:!1},{text:"  Those who will justify the work",correct:!1},{text:"  A random group of technical specialists ",correct:!1},{text:"  The engine room of the project",correct:!0}]},{question:"A person assuming a Solution Developer role should ideally be allocated to the project on what basis?",answers:[{text:"  From a consultancy background",correct:!1},{text:"  Full time for the work they will do on the project",correct:!0},{text:"  For the duration of a single development Timebox",correct:!1},{text:"  From a senior management level within the business",correct:!1}]},{question:"As the project's technical design authority, the Technical Coordinator ensures that the Solution Development Teams (SDTs) work in a consistent way, that the project is technically coherent and meets the:",answers:[{text:"  Desired technical quality standards ",correct:!0},{text:"  Demands set out by the users",correct:!1},{text:"  Full business benefits",correct:!1},{text:"  Customer's quality expectations",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Technical Advisor supports the Solution Development Team (SDT) through the provision of detailed and often specialist technical input and advice with regards to ________:",answers:[{text:"  Assurance that the solution is evolving correctly ",correct:!0},{text:"  Confirmation that the benefits will be achieved ",correct:!1},{text:"  Compliance with Corporate standards",correct:!1},{text:"  Compliance with Regulatory standards",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role is a leadership role rather than a management role and the person holding it will ideally be elected by his or her peers?",answers:[{text:"  Solution Tester ",correct:!1},{text:"  Team Leader",correct:!0},{text:"  Solution Developer ",correct:!1},{text:"  Project Manager",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role in an AgilePM project team acts as a final arbiter of any disagreements between team members?",answers:[{text:"  Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"  Technical Coordinator ",correct:!1},{text:"  Business Visionary",correct:!0},{text:"  Project Manager",correct:!1}]},{question:"The DSDM Coach should ideally be:",answers:[{text:"  The Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"  An external consultant",correct:!1},{text:"  An experienced Team Leader who can also act as Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"  Certified as a DSDM Coach to ensure competence to fulfil this role has been independently validated",correct:!0}]},{question:"The Business Visionary remains involved throughout the project providing the team with strategic direction and ensuring that the solution delivered will:",answers:[{text:"  Be able to be used by the receiving community",correct:!1},{text:"  Have been developed to the highest possible standard",correct:!1},{text:"  Enable the benefits described in the Business Case to be achieved ",correct:!0},{text:"  Comply with all technical requirements",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM identifies roles in three categories. Which is the correct combination?",answers:[{text:"Project, Technical Development and Other",correct:!1},{text:"Business, Project and Finance",correct:!1},{text:"Maintenance, Finance and Project",correct:!1},{text:"Project, Solution Development and Other",correct:!0}]},{question:"Business Visionary .",answers:[{text:"agrees and controls the technical architecture",correct:!1},{text:"defines the business vision for the project",correct:!0},{text:"ensures business resources are available as needed",correct:!1},{text:"resolves technical differences between technical team members",correct:!1}]},{question:"Technical Coordinator .",answers:[{text:"is performs testing in accordance with Technical Testing Strategy",correct:!1},{text:"is managing technical aspects of the transition of the solution into live use",correct:!0},{text:"is determining the business environments",correct:!1},{text:"is fully integrated with Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!1}]},{question:"Project Manager ________.",answers:[{text:"is brought in on ad-hoc basis as and when needed",correct:!1},{text:"is a catalyst for workshop preparation and communication",correct:!1},{text:"is coaching the SDT when handling difficult situations",correct:!0},{text:"is fully integrated with SDT",correct:!1}]},{question:"Business Analyst ________.",answers:[{text:"works with team to plan and co-ordinate all aspects of product delivery at detailed level",correct:!1},{text:"is fully available for Project Manager request",correct:!1},{text:"interprets business requirements and translates them into a deployable solution",correct:!1},{text:"ensures business needs are properly analysed and correctly reflected evolution of solution",correct:!0}]},{question:"    213.Team Leader .",answers:[{text:"is resourcing Specialist Roles as required",correct:!1},{text:"ensures team functions as a whole and meets objectives",correct:!0},{text:"is ideally selected by Steering Committee",correct:!1},{text:"provides command and control, rather than space for creativity",correct:!1}]},{question:"Workshop Facilitator is responsible for ________.",answers:[{text:"workshop content, not the context",correct:!1},{text:"workshop content and the context",correct:!1},{text:"neither the workshop content and the context",correct:!1},{text:"workshop context, not the content",correct:!0}]},{question:"Which of the following lists contains only SDT roles?",answers:[{text:"Business Ambassador, Solution Developer, Solution Tester",correct:!0},{text:"Team Leader, Business Visionary, Business Advisor",correct:!1},{text:"Facilitator, Business Advisor, DSDM Coach",correct:!1},{text:"Business Ambassador, Solution Tester, Agile Trainer",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM provides specialist input to solution development or testing?",answers:[{text:"Business Ambassador",correct:!1},{text:"Business Visionary",correct:!1},{text:"Business Sponsor",correct:!1},{text:"Business Advisor",correct:!0}]},{question:"Which role in AgilePM focuses on NFRs (non-functional requirements) if they are achievable?",answers:[{text:"Technical Coordinator",correct:!0},{text:"Teal Leader",correct:!1},{text:"Solution Developer",correct:!1},{text:"Solution Tester",correct:!1}]},{question:"It is possible to have Specialist roles at the Project level. A common example of a Project level specialist    role would be which of the following?",answers:[{text:"Technical specialist",correct:!1},{text:"A second Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"Operations Coordinator",correct:!0},{text:"Programme strategist",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Team Leader works with the team to plan and co-ordinate all aspects of:",answers:[{text:"Project and corporate strategy alignment",correct:!1},{text:"Product delivery at the detailed level",correct:!0},{text:"Product delivery at the high level",correct:!1},{text:"Project performance",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Workshop Facilitator is responsible for managing the workshop process and is the:",answers:[{text:"Sole point of contact for the Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!1},{text:"Chairperson for all Daily Stand-Ups",correct:!1},{text:"Catalyst for preparation and communication",correct:!0},{text:"Remover of all roadblocks affecting team performance",correct:!1}]},{question:"The Business Analyst is fully integrated with Solution Development Team (SDT) and focuses on which of the    following aspects of the project?",answers:[{text:"The relationship between the business and technical roles",correct:!0},{text:"Developing the most useful solution possible",correct:!1},{text:"Delivering the benefits after Deployment",correct:!1},{text:"Managing the project to a successful conclusion",correct:!1}]},{question:"What role is the catalyst for preparation and communication and should be independent of the outcome to be    achieved in the workshop?",answers:[{text:"Workshop Facilitator",correct:!0},{text:"Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"Solution Developer",correct:!1}]},{question:"The ________ interprets business requirements and translates them into a deployable solution that meets    functional and non-functional needs",answers:[{text:"Business Analyst",correct:!1},{text:"Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"Solution Developer",correct:!0},{text:"Project Manager",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which statement correctly describes how people may be assigned to an AgilePM project team?",answers:[{text:"One person may cover two or more roles and a role may be split between two or more people",correct:!0},{text:"Each role should be taken by only one person",correct:!1},{text:"A person delegated to the team may take on only one role",correct:!1},{text:"All team members must be seconded full time to the project",correct:!1}]},{question:"Working closely with the rest of the Solution Development Team (SDT), the Business Ambassador:",answers:[{text:"Ensures that the business needs are properly analysed",correct:!1},{text:"Replaces the need for a Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"Guides the evolution of the solution",correct:!0},{text:"Tests every part of the developed solution",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM advocates the use of models to improve communication and to create or challenge ideas by:",answers:[{text:"Providing fully functioning devices for final inspection",correct:!1},{text:"Revealing the Won't Haves",correct:!1},{text:"Organising a Facilitated Workshop",correct:!1},{text:"Making developing products visible",correct:!0}]},{question:"The Project Manager or Business Analyst should challenge requirements if they are not obvious Must Haves but    whose responsibility is it to prove a requirement is a Must Have?",answers:[{text:"Business Analyst",correct:!1},{text:"Business Visionary",correct:!0},{text:"Solution Developer",correct:!1},{text:"Team Leader",correct:!1}]},{question:"In AgilePM, the Business Ambassador knows what is needed, the Solution Developers know how to evolve the    product and the Business Ambassador and Business Advisors in collaboration with the Solution Testers are responsible    for which of the following?",answers:[{text:"Judging whether the resulting product is fit for purpose",correct:!0},{text:"Determining whether the product is ready for testing",correct:!1},{text:"The Prioritised Requirements List",correct:!1},{text:"Facilitated Workshops",correct:!1}]},{question:"Facilitated Workshops are a specialised type of meeting, with a clear objective (product), a workshop owner,    who needs the outcome of the workshop and is the:",answers:[{text:"Driver for it to happen",correct:!0},{text:"Chairperson of all meetings",correct:!1},{text:"Most senior person on the project team",correct:!1},{text:"Intended user of the solution",correct:!1}]},{question:"The aim of which iteration of a Timebox is to complete as much of the development work as possible including    testing the deliverable(s)?",answers:[{text:"Refinement",correct:!0},{text:"Consolidation",correct:!1},{text:"Investigation",correct:!1},{text:"Close-out",correct:!1}]},{question:"Solution Quality has to encompass not just customer satisfaction (although this is a key measure), but also:",answers:[{text:"Regulatory compliance",correct:!1},{text:"User agreement",correct:!1},{text:"Technical and support concerns",correct:!0},{text:"Architectural coherence",correct:!1}]},{question:"In an AgilePM project requirements evolve as the project progresses. As this happens they become which of the    following?",answers:[{text:"Less detailed",correct:!1},{text:"Highly involved",correct:!1},{text:"Less possible to produce economically",correct:!1},{text:"More detailed",correct:!0}]},{question:"Which of the following statements correctly defines what the project team has agreed it will do about the Won't    have's?",answers:[{text:"Deliver if time and cost permit",correct:!1},{text:"Start a new project to deliver",correct:!1},{text:"Not deliver",correct:!0},{text:"Be impossible to produce and deliver",correct:!1}]},{question:"Since AgilePM is all about time-driven solutions, successful AgilePM projects typically focus on delivering a    working solution on time, rather than:",answers:[{text:"Testing for total compliance",correct:!1},{text:"Waiting for an even better solution late",correct:!0},{text:"Overspending on a more attractive product",correct:!1},{text:"Renegotiating Terms of Reference (ToR)",correct:!1}]},{question:"At the lowest level of detail there will be a point where the requirement does not need to be written down.    When this point is achieved what should happen to the requirement?",answers:[{text:"Prioritised as a Won't Have",correct:!1},{text:"Omitted from the solution being developed",correct:!1},{text:"Built directly into the solution",correct:!0},{text:"Referred to the Business Sponsor for decision making",correct:!1}]},{question:"The aim of Investigation is to provide a firm foundation for the work to be carried out during which other    iteration of a Timebox?",answers:[{text:"Consolidation",correct:!1},{text:"Refinement",correct:!0},{text:"Close-out",correct:!1},{text:"Kick off",correct:!1}]},{question:"A Should Have may be differentiated from a Could Have by reviewing the degree of:",answers:[{text:"Unhappiness in the organisation by it not being met",correct:!1},{text:"Loss of benefit by it not being met",correct:!1},{text:"Risk generated by it not being met",correct:!1},{text:"Pain caused by it not being met",correct:!0}]},{question:"Ask the question 'What happens if this requirement is not met?' If the answer is 'Cancel the project - there is    no point in implementing a solution that does not meet this requirement' then it is a:",answers:[{text:"Must Have requirement",correct:!0},{text:"Should Have requirement",correct:!1},{text:"Could Have requirement",correct:!1},{text:"Won't Have requirement",correct:!1}]},{question:"The emphasis in AgilePM remains on ensuring that any models used enhance communication and are as clearly    understood by which of the following?",answers:[{text:"Senior management",correct:!1},{text:"The Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!1},{text:"Business Ambassador",correct:!1},{text:"The intended audience as by the creators",correct:!0}]},{question:"The aim of the Kick-off is to review the Timebox objectives to gain which of the following?",answers:[{text:"Full agreement that the solution is achievable",correct:!1},{text:"Business consent that the work can commence",correct:!1},{text:"Common understanding of what is to be achieved",correct:!0},{text:"Certification that the product will meet regulatory requirements",correct:!1}]},{question:"The AgilePM approach to requirements involves establishing the requirements early, at a high level during the    Feasibility and Foundations Phases, agreeing these with the:",answers:[{text:"Team Leader",correct:!1},{text:"Business Sponsor",correct:!0},{text:"Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"Business Visionary",correct:!1}]},{question:"As part of AgilePM's drive for clear and continuous communication what does it offer as having significant    benefits in making ideas, situations and options visible?",answers:[{text:"Modelling",correct:!0},{text:"Displaying",correct:!1},{text:"Graphing",correct:!1},{text:"Monitoring",correct:!1}]},{question:"Every Timebox can be considered as beginning with a Kick-off and ending with:",answers:[{text:"Agreement by everyone involved",correct:!1},{text:"Project closure",correct:!1},{text:"Approval of the evolved solution",correct:!1},{text:"A Close-out meeting",correct:!0}]},{question:"The cycles of Identify, Plan, Evolve and Review, combined with the structure of the ________, comprising    iterations of Investigation, Refinement and Consolidation, ensure that the iterative process is well controlled",answers:[{text:"Defined Testing Protocols",correct:!1},{text:"Solution Development Timebox",correct:!0},{text:"Solution Development Team (SDT)",correct:!1},{text:"Project Plan",correct:!1}]},{question:"MoSCoW is a technique for helping to understand:",answers:[{text:"Geography",correct:!1},{text:"Priorities",correct:!0},{text:"People",correct:!1},{text:"Practices",correct:!1}]},{question:"During an AgilePM project, there are key points in the early stages ________ where quality decisions need to be    made. The reason for making these decisions early is so that everyone involved in the project clearly understands    what is and what is not acceptable.",answers:[{text:"limited to Pre-Project",correct:!1},{text:"at the Project Manager's discretion",correct:!1},{text:"up to and including Foundations",correct:!0},{text:"determined by the Business Sponsor",correct:!1}]},{question:"The factors which have been found, in practice, to greatly improve the success of Facilitated Workshop are an    effective, trained, independent:",answers:[{text:"DSDM Coach",correct:!1},{text:"Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"Workshop Facilitator",correct:!0},{text:"Workshop Owner",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM proposes that the Project Manager should make sure that two things are in place at the beginning of    each Solution Development Timebox. One is properly formulated Solution Foundations to guide development, what is the    other?",answers:[{text:"Well defined testing parameters",correct:!1},{text:"Adequate resources for the development",correct:!1},{text:"Properly defined acceptance criteria",correct:!0},{text:"No roadblocks which could hinder iterative development",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM advocates clear and continuous communication using rich communication techniques. Which of the    following does AgilePM consider to be key aspects of communication?",answers:[{text:"Monthly meetings to discuss progress",correct:!1},{text:"The development of models and prototypes",correct:!0},{text:"Detailed plans for the development of features provided by the Project Manager",correct:!1},{text:"Face to face discussions with written up minutes",correct:!1}]},{question:"Facilitated Workshops lead to participants feeling more involved and:",answers:[{text:"A quicker route to a solution being developed",correct:!1},{text:"More able to leave the project when times are tough",correct:!1},{text:"Project Managers able to manage better",correct:!1},{text:"Committed to the end results",correct:!0}]},{question:"The MoSCoW rules have been cast in a way that allows the delivery of the ________ of requirements to be    guaranteed",answers:[{text:"Minimum Usable Subset",correct:!0},{text:"best Possible Solution",correct:!1},{text:"lowest level",correct:!1},{text:"Maximum Usable Subset",correct:!1}]},{question:"In AgilePM, quality is about delivering a solution that is fit for purpose which means delivering a working    solution which meets?",answers:[{text:"Agreed acceptance criteria",correct:!0},{text:"Customer quality expectations",correct:!1},{text:"80% of the agreed requirements",correct:!1},{text:"User acceptance testing",correct:!1}]},{question:"Which of the following statements correctly defines a non-functional requirement?",answers:[{text:"A service that needs to be provided",correct:!1},{text:"How well something is to be carried out",correct:!0},{text:"Functionality that may fail in service without detriment to the business",correct:!1},{text:"A feature that can safely be left out of the deployed solution",correct:!1}]},{question:"Provided the team can demonstrate control over what they are doing, it is important that the Project Manager    employs what form of management over the team?",answers:[{text:"Management by directive",correct:!1},{text:"Control and command",correct:!1},{text:"Manage by objectives",correct:!1},{text:"Management by exception",correct:!0}]},{question:"Models and prototypes will help to analyse and present some of the required technical information in:",answers:[{text:"Sequential iterations",correct:!1},{text:"Written form",correct:!1},{text:"Manageable increments",correct:!0},{text:"Management stages",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM recommends controlling via a cycle of three iterations - Investigation, Refinement, ________",answers:[{text:"Testing",correct:!1},{text:"Consolidation",correct:!0},{text:"Deployment",correct:!1},{text:"Rework",correct:!1}]},{question:"Iterative development is a process where the delivery of a product results from a repeated cycle of development    activity where each execution of the cycle yields a result successively closer to a desired outcome:",answers:[{text:"Until a perfect solution is developed",correct:!1},{text:"Resulting in a fully capable product",correct:!1},{text:"Converging on an accurate solution",correct:!0},{text:"Acceptable to the customer",correct:!1}]},{question:"Facilitated Workshops are a process in which a neutral facilitator, with no stake in the outcome of the    workshop, enables a group to work together to ________, whether that be solving a problem, building a plan,    gathering requirements or making a decision.",answers:[{text:"develop the solution",correct:!1},{text:"appoint the Business Sponsor",correct:!1},{text:"identify the business strategy",correct:!1},{text:"achieve an agreed goal",correct:!0}]},{question:"At its simplest, a requirement is a service, feature or function that the user wishes the solution to:",answers:[{text:"Perform or exhibit",correct:!0},{text:"Be capable of showing a return on investment",correct:!1},{text:"Be incapable of performing or exhibiting",correct:!1},{text:"Display",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM proposes that participants of a Facilitated Workshop should receive a workshop report very soon after    the workshop closes. What timescale is recommended by AgilePM for the distribution of the report?",answers:[{text:"Within 48 hours",correct:!0},{text:"After a week",correct:!1},{text:"Before the Workshop formally ends",correct:!1},{text:"Within 4 hours by email",correct:!1}]},{question:"Timeboxing is a key technique in AgilePM. It is a well defined process to control the creation of low-level    products in an iterative fashion, with:",answers:[{text:"Several specific review points",correct:!0},{text:"Automatic correction features built in",correct:!1},{text:"Control exercised by the Business Sponsor",correct:!1},{text:"No need for any reviews",correct:!1}]},{question:"Why does a Facilitated Workshop make it possible for everyone to communicate and collaborate effectively with    each other and have greater confidence in the result?",answers:[{text:"All participants are given written invitations to attend",correct:!1},{text:"All relevant stakeholders are present at the same time",correct:!0},{text:"Full minutes of all discussions are written up and distributed within an hour of the end of a workshop",correct:!1},{text:"Only the most effective people may attend, keeping the discussions short",correct:!1}]},{question:"AgilePM advocates that there should be open discussions on Solution Quality from the start of the project,    therefore, it suggests that Solution Quality should be part of which management product(s)?",answers:[{text:"Business Case",correct:!1},{text:"Increment Review Record",correct:!1},{text:"Timebox Review Record",correct:!1},{text:"All plans",correct:!0}]},{question:"How the Exploration and Engineering phases overlap, merge and flip from one to the other is left to a    particular project to decide based on the:",answers:[{text:"Nature of the solution being created",correct:!0},{text:"Preferences of the Solution Tester alone",correct:!1},{text:"Directives from senior management",correct:!1},{text:"Resources available",correct:!1}]},{question:"Earned value analysis is a standard measure used throughout industry to control projects. Its basis is defined    by which of the following?",answers:[{text:"Measuring the value that has been earned to date in the project",correct:!0},{text:"Analysing the benefits each deployed feature brings to the business",correct:!1},{text:"Understanding the total cost spent by the project to date",correct:!1},{text:"Evaluating the return on investment",correct:!1}]},{question:"Initial estimates during Feasibility will be based on the limited information known about the project at this    stage, but also on:",answers:[{text:"Statistical evidence from wide range of projects",correct:!1},{text:"An average cost of the last few projects undertaken by the team",correct:!1},{text:"The judgement call of the Business Sponsor",correct:!1},{text:"Experience of similar solutions in different projects",correct:!0}]},{question:"Objectives of the Feasibility phase are to describe the organisation and:",answers:[{text:"Management skills required",correct:!1},{text:"Deployment team needs",correct:!1},{text:"Governance aspects of the project",correct:!0},{text:"Senior management involvement with the solution evolution",correct:!1}]},{question:"Allow the people doing the work to estimate:",answers:[{text:"No-one else can do it",correct:!1},{text:"They have a vested interest in being right",correct:!0},{text:"Their opinion is always right",correct:!1},{text:"Everyone else is too busy",correct:!1}]},{question:"In considering product maintainability one option is to 'deliver first, re-engineer later'. In that case the    business priority is to elicit and ________ the required functionality quickly",answers:[{text:"develop",correct:!1},{text:"test",correct:!1},{text:"design",correct:!1},{text:"implement",correct:!0}]},{question:"Which two functions are used to derive a value of team velocity?",answers:[{text:"Effort and output",correct:!0},{text:"Time and cost",correct:!1},{text:"Output and waste",correct:!1},{text:"Planned time and actual time",correct:!1}]}],b=o(29),y=o.n(b),q=function(e){Object(h.a)(o,e);var t=Object(u.a)(o);function o(e){var r;return Object(c.a)(this,o),(r=t.call(this,e)).state={displayedAnswer:r.filterQuestions("")},r.onFilterChange=r.onFilterChange.bind(Object(l.a)(r)),r}return Object(a.a)(o,[{key:"filterQuestions",value:function(e){var t=this,o=[],r=i.a.createElement("span",{role:"img","aria-label":"correct"},"\u2705"),n=i.a.createElement("span",{role:"img","aria-label":"incorrect"},"\u274c");return y.a.forEach(v,(function(s){(""===e||s.question.toLowerCase().includes(e.toLowerCase())||t.answerIncludeKeyword(s.answers,e))&&o.push(i.a.createElement(p.a,{item:!0,xs:12,sm:6},i.a.createElement(x.a,{style:{animation:w.animations.popIn,backgroundColor:"rgba(253, 247, 237, 0.4)",maxWidth:"95%",margin:"0 auto",height:"auto"}},i.a.createElement(f.a,null,i.a.createElement(g.a,{color:"textPrimary",gutterBottom:!0},i.a.createElement("b",null,s.question)),i.a.createElement("p",{style:{lineHeight:"1.5"}},s.answers[0].correct?r:n," ",i.a.createElement("span",null,s.answers[0].text),i.a.createElement("br",null),i.a.createElement("br",null),s.answers[1].correct?r:n," ",i.a.createElement("span",null,s.answers[1].text),i.a.createElement("br",null),i.a.createElement("br",null),s.answers[2].correct?r:n," ",i.a.createElement("span",null,s.answers[2].text),i.a.createElement("br",null),i.a.createElement("br",null),s.answers[3].correct?r:n," ",i.a.createElement("span",null,s.answers[3].text),i.a.createElement("br",null),i.a.createElement("br",null))))))})),o}},{key:"answerIncludeKeyword",value:function(e,t){for(var o=0;o<e.length;o++)if(e[o].text.toLowerCase().includes(t.toLowerCase()))return!0;return!1}},{key:"onFilterChange",value:function(e){this.setState({displayedAnswer:this.filterQuestions(e.currentTarget.value)})}},{key:"render",value:function(){var e=this.props.classes;return i.a.createElement("div",{className:e.root},i.a.createElement(p.a,{container:!0,className:e.container,spacing:3},i.a.createElement(p.a,{item:!0,xs:12},i.a.createElement(m.a,{id:"filled-basic",label:"Keyword",variant:"outlined",onChange:this.onFilterChange,fullWidth:!0})),this.state.displayedAnswer))}}]),o}(i.a.Component),T=Object(d.a)((function(e){return{root:{height:"100%",width:"100%",position:"absolute",top:"0",left:"0"},container:{width:"95%",maxWidth:"800px",margin:"0 auto",marginTop:"100px"}}}))(q);o(48),Boolean("localhost"===window.location.hostname||"[::1]"===window.location.hostname||window.location.hostname.match(/^127(?:\.(?:25[0-5]|2[0-4][0-9]|[01]?[0-9][0-9]?)){3}$/));s.a.render(i.a.createElement(i.a.StrictMode,null,i.a.createElement("link",{rel:"stylesheet",href:"https://fonts.googleapis.com/icon?family=Material+Icons"}),i.a.createElement(T,null)),document.getElementById("root")),"serviceWorker"in navigator&&navigator.serviceWorker.ready.then((function(e){e.unregister()})).catch((function(e){console.error(e.message)}))}},[[37,1,2]]]);
//# sourceMappingURL=main.13401d50.chunk.js.map